So, uh, yeah, early early pod this week.
Uh, we've got some, uh, good bits, some,
um, pieces. We've got, uh, we got to
talk about probably the big teams
really. Arsenal, how how many games has
he got? He's on the edge. Feels like um,
people bit confused by Liverpool. I
think this I think I don't think we've
had a Premier League season where people
have been this confused about all the
teams.
Which team are you absolutely certain
are brilliant?
I don't want to say it.
Has given an A.
I don't know. I can't answer that
question because the only answer I've
got is the one I don't want to say.
Yes, it might begin with an A.
Right. All right. Well, cuz I've got on
here, Arsenal, are they good?
Simple question. We can discuss that if
you'd like.
Well, yeah, I'd love to discuss that,
but just not right at the beginning,
like sort of middling so that if any of
our fans do watch, they have to work for
it.
Sure.
Is that fair?
Understandable. Understandable. Last
week, we got annoyed about I got annoyed
about Ekitica getting booked for taking
his shirt off. Um, and I yeah, I was
just intrigued to know uh it well it was
intriguing to find out what people
think. Some people were saying so Paul
Casey, shout out to Paul Casey this week
who I know has been uh speaking Japanese
for a long time and uh he did a comment
and then I'm scrolling down and he must
have just sort of kept watching and he's
made another comment on the same issue.
Not something I see a lot of if I'm
honest,
but both of enough quality for me to go,
"Yeah, I'll have that one." And then I
go, "Yeah, I'll have that one as well."
And they were both Paul Cases. Well
done, Paul.
Two comments at different times in
clearly in the podcast. One's one's like
much much later on, both five days ago,
so both in the same sitting, I think.
Um, but and yeah, I don't I'd love to
know if uh of of our dry slugs, how many
of you are double dippers or you know,
do you save yourself for when do you
comment? Do you comment in the heat of
the moment? Do you com do you sort of
gather your thoughts because I want this
to be good so it might get read out like
where is everyone at?
It's funny you say that cuz some people
might be watch listening to the audio
version of this on Spotify and I found
that the comments on Spotify the
spiciest it's the spiciest place on
earth
on Spotify. Very prickly.
They are very prickly. That's
interesting.
Have you noticed this?
I think I have now. Now you're saying
it.
I think I know why.
Prickly. Go on. Faceless.
Yes. Potentially. But I think moreover
they usually in a podcast you're
separated by something, right? You're
not able to comment directly in that
moment and lots of points are made over
a long period of time on a on a podcast.
But on Spotify, they're looking at the
podcast. the comments options are right
there as you listen and you you you're
able to comment when you're most
triggered by whatever's been discussed,
right?
Go. There's less
Yeah.
balance in Spotify comments.
Do you think as well with Spotify
because it's still it's it's in the it's
just a baby when it comes to commenting
commentating comment commenting that uh
you know, you've got to really want it.
You got to really have an axe either an
axe to grind or some love to give. And
love's love you can keep within, can't
you? It's nice to hold that glow. But
when it's when it's angry, you want to
get the poison out.
Get it out.
Yeah. Um
Yeah. Paul, the big question Matt
Bradbury says, the big question, Paul,
is was it in the same poo?
How many I reckon there's about 10% of
our audience that watch us mid poo?
What?
I don't feel comfortable if I'm going
for a p. I don't want other people's
faces.
Someone's someone's listening or
watching this right now
and they they probably just just as I've
just before I've said it, they've gone
and
here this could be a new bit, right? Do
you know is like
the what's a weird love pang? Right?
Ready? Do you know what love pang is?
Uh so I think I could guess but go on. A
love pang is when so I'll send my
beloved wife of eight years anniversary
this week.
Yeah. Um
close up.
That's a love pang. That's a love.
Yeah. Love wang. That is the uh No, the
love pang is if I sometimes you get like
a feeling or you remember something and
you get ah you're like ah
got a little love pang there
and I and uh I'll send fam a little
message when when I get a love pang.
often we code who
I wonder who pangs the most.
Yeah.
Uh
I reckon you pang the most.
Yeah. Quite a feeling based person,
aren't I? It would seem. So So yeah, I I
probably do pang. I pang regularly. And
uh but yeah, do you know a very strange
thing love pang I have with my son is
when you got to take him to have a to go
to the toilet. Now, normally he's like
buzzing about looking around, right?
He's doing all sorts. But when he then
goes to strain, he gives you this like
death, not death stare. It's not fair.
It's just intense like
[Laughter]
and you get to look at him in all his
you get not all his glory, but like you
get to look at him for a long period of
time and he's looking at you for a long
period of time. So you get this bizarre
like I you get the love pang of like oh
my god I love you so much but you are
this isn't the
yeah this isn't the ideal moment maybe
do you do that with your partner people
out there you know does how long does
that go on for
mate anyway if you is there a always
scanning yeah that's it that's f he's
going to be a player
he went to uh he went to football
training this morning and and uh my
my parents came back and they said and
They were she my mom came through the
door and she went he liked it.
I was like yeah
wearing his QPR kit.
So So this people won't know about this
but I stayed over at James' house when
we were doing some work for I can't
remember sport Bible.
Yeah.
And um and and so he was going to
football training and James wanted him
to wear for obvious reasons a QPR shirt.
However,
James' wife wants him to fit in. So, he
doesn't want to feel awkward when he
goes to the football training.
Yeah.
And they haven't they have already
agreed kit that all the kids would wear.
So, they all feel like they belong to
the same team.
James,
one of us is white. One of us is an
ethnic minority. You guess. You guess
which one's which. See, I'm I'm
desperate. I'm feel free. I want to be
different. Poor Poor Stacy. She's
thinking, "Look, just let the kid fit
in."
Oh, I see. I wonder I didn't know where
you was going, but I guess you get
nervous. Yeah, just Yeah, a little bit.
Yeah, but then you're talking about your
own family, so what can you say? You can
say what you like.
Take it. So,
you can pretty much say what you like, I
think. Um, yeah, but I love the fact
that James said no.
The boys wear boys got to wear his kit.
Yeah,
his kit, doesn't he?
Um, anyway, yeah, he worked today and he
was
Before we get into the crux of this
episode, Jim, I've got something that's
been bothering me. You know this.
Go on.
Give me his full name. Carl Hines
Rumiger.
Rumiger. Um he you nervous to say that
name.
Don't acknowledge it then it's not a
problem.
Right. That's his name. Kh rumiger.
Yeah. No. Don't stop. Let's now you've
made it a thing.
Why?
Now I can't.
Because you
That's his name though, isn't it?
What I'm saying? I'm trying to wash it
away. You don't need to feel worried
about saying the last part of his name.
You brought it up. You brought it up. I
didn't say anything at all.
Okay.
I was just saying why did you get me to
say what did you do? I know when you're
going cuz you'll you'll have a go at the
name. you normally you'll have a go at
the name
and then have a laugh about it whereas
this goes oh James
I couldn't remember his first name was
Carl Hines that's why so I gambled on
cohines and you you were really quick to
say it weirdly you might be waiting for
this
um he has come out and he's called
Newcastle idiots for stumping up 65
million pound for what could be the
greatest nine football has ever seen in
Nick Wmire
um all right he's not going be that. But
he is a lovely player and I like him.
He's two [ __ ] brilliant oldfashioned
Duncan Fergusones headers first. Yeah.
Yeah.
But he's Yeah. Anyway
and I'm like and he's like oh no they're
idiots in England there's an idiot tax
because we got so much money. You got by
So he says Stokart must have been over
the mind to find idiots uh extreme
enough to pay 65 million pound or 80
million euros for Tomato because
obviously Bayern Munich wanted to buy
them as well. Yeah.
Hang on a minute.
Sour. What's What's Hang on.
Let me just see what it is in German.
German. Yeah.
Yeah.
Hang on a second. Isn't Aren't you the
club that do this to all the other
German football clubs? You're the
financial powerhouse.
Zen,
I can even play. I'll play it for you.
Zora.
And if you like,
you can't hear it, but people will be
able to hear in the pod.
Zhaen.
Yeah.
Uh it's not just him, it's the other
directors as well. They're all putting
their foot in. They're all putting their
boot in it.
And it's because they wanted Volto Mada.
And it's for obvious reasons that
Newcastle overpaid.
You would say they they paid more, but
the circumstances
is what's really winding me up. And the
sort of the you know, it's double
standards because how much they've spent
on Lewis Diaz? 75 million100 million
pound for Harry Kane [ __ ] Alise come
and picking Alisa like they can do what
they want in that league and win it.
They've there's been one winner in the
last 13 seasons once has one other team
won it other than Bayern Munich and that
was Leverkusen. M
so
don't like don't like then then because
you you haven't been able to get one
player then sort of go oh I know idiots
because they're willing to pay east it
was eack money that Newcastle spend
why are you so angry about this
because I don't know actually I don't I
was just listening to it and I was like
[ __ ] annoyed I'm I'm still bitter
that they they managed to get Bayern
Munich sorry Harry Kane out of us
right
and I'm like that is
Matt Bradbury one of our beloved
moist slugs. We've got some great
comments this week, by the way, from dry
and moist. One person who has become
moist, which I'll I'll read out in a
bit. But if you do want to join us,
become a patron, please do. Uh we do a
bonus podcast where we just talk about
stuff that isn't really football. And
it's I think a lot of the moisties think
it's actually better than this. So, uh
if you would like to join us, then
please do. Um but anyway, Matt Bradbury
says, "Jaffen has already solved this
one years ago. Once you've got the money
to spend, you've got to spend it. That
is how that Sorry. Once you've got the
money to spend and you've spent it, that
is how much the player is worth. Next.
Next.
Yeah.
Yes. Someone tell [ __ ] Romania this.
It is a wo What did you say? The It is a
woeful take. It's
the thing you got to do though. You got
you got to step away. You got to step
away from getting
cuz he's he's getting pissy because he's
not got his own way. Right. So
I think it's it's about a cal calm push
back here that the point is is the
market is the market is the market and
as you said
it's look the money that they've been
able to spend is and the money that have
taken and asked for is based on the very
clear knowledge that you've just made a
load of money on isach and this happens
Like so forget the leagues for a second
and look the league there is a Premier
League tax and they're kind of they kind
of should be
should be yeah
because they have got the money and
that's how negotiations work like if
you're negotiating with like in YouTube
like if you've got certain brand certain
brands you could kind of go well no I I
know you I know you've not got much
money you're a you know you're a startup
blah blah blah whatever or like or
you're a charity or whatever it might be
but when it's like when It's like when
it's a bigger brand, you go, "Well, I
should be able to kind of
be a bit punchy here." And that's
exactly the same. The same goes the one
I always think of is Middlesbrough sold
I think they sold like Jed Spence and
they sold a couple of other players for
like big money couple of seasons ago. I
think when Chris Wilder was the manager
and and and so they were then looking
for players that would come to the
championship
and all the other teams were kind of
holding them to ransom a little bit
because
they've got money. So, it's it's just
they should everyone should be kind of
paying a bit more and
it's about like the pain percentage I
think
like
the fact that you've got this you know
the fact you've got that amount of money
to be able to spend means that you can
spend that money which means that's how
much he's worth to you the end.
Can I just ask is there an option to buy
a Nicholas Jan Jackson deal to Bayern
Munich from Chelsea?
Say that again.
Is there an option to buy?
I think so.
Yes, I would think so as well. Right.
So, let me there's a couple of things I
want to pick apart in terms of this
deal.
There is an option to buy which is worth
70.5 million for Nicholas Jackson.
Yeah. Which is a
You would on paper would have to say
Nicholas Jackson because he scored goals
in the Premier League, but we all know
he isn't, right? We all know he's bit
rubbish, but but Bayern Munich have
agreed to do it.
Secondly, they have paid a loan fee to
Chelsea of 14.3 million, which is about
a third n about a quarter more or less
of what has cost Newcastle. So what are
you even talking about? I did actually
find it funny though when one of the
director
and is the 14 million sorry is the 14
million is that aside or as part of like
if you have to pay whatever that number
was you said was it 70 something
is that 14 on top of the 70?
No t typically loan
the loan fee comes off of the option to
buy.
Right. Right. Got you.
Typically typically
makes sense. Um, yeah. So, so,
so we're in, we're in a situation where
it doesn't really make much sense.
They're just bitter that they haven't
been able to. And what more do you need
to win the league? You've got possibly
the best striker in in in in the world
already. You've got Elise, who's an
unbelievable talent. You've got your
team is so much. You bought Palinia for
close to 60 million pound and didn't
even play him.
What are you on about?
I don't know why I'm angry about it. I
don't know why why I'm angry about it. I
I just
It's very sour. It's It's sour and it's
It's really sour. It's really sour. It's
really unnecessary as well. Like move
on. Move on.
Shut up. It happened like two weeks ago,
you [ __ ] And also three weeks ago.
And also, James, isn't this good? This
is brilliant for German football and
brilliant for Stokart. They are funding
your league.
Yeah. I also I think the fact that he's
you know a German international and will
be for the foreseeable future.
I find that weird as well. Like it's
like he's like triple bitter because you
know a fellow German shouldn't be doing
this. Like you should be choosing Bayern
Munich who are you know there's always a
not joke or it's a known thing that
Germany is Bayern. you know, partly down
to because you got better players, but
also there's always a feeling that the
players that should be in the team end
up not being in the team because Bayern
Munich players get in the team. So, I
don't know, maybe that's playing a part
in it. I think there's a double um
there's an element of embarrassment for
a very
someone who's clearly got quite an ego
here that like we Munich, what on earth
are you doing?
Yeah, there's a few people in the chat
going, we know why you're hungry. Sorry,
hungry. What I'm talking about?
We know why. I'm not actually. We know
why you're angry. It's because they took
Kane and I'm like, "Yeah, because
weirdly, Jim, weirdly because I'm I
belong to a club that's in the Premier
League. I think I'm better than Bayern
Munich."
All right. Sorry. Dig at me.
You think you're better than me? Do you
think you're better than me then?
No, I not you, Jim. Probably
about it. Thanks for taking Thanks for
taking the question seriously.
Appreciate it.
Let me explain. Jim,
am I better than you because the team
you didn't have a choice in supporting
isn't in the same league as mine?
The right answer is no, isn't it? No.
No. I I don't I don't think I'm better
than you in any shape or form. Right.
But all the other QPR fans 100%.
Yeah.
Okay.
Um Yeah. Careful. Uh, Paul Paul
McCallendon. Another Paul here. Um, have
a nibble on some bread, Flav. You know
you have it next to you.
Have you got any food near you? That's a
good thing.
I'm not hungry. I'm not hungry.
Have you got food near you, though? Have
you got like safety food near you?
Not safety food. I got some of that, but
shouldn't show that.
That's
free. It I've got um I've got water.
I've got and I've got I've got the
snacks I steal from Spotify. Every time
I leave Spotify, I steal loads of
snacks.
Got a snack. Um Luke's trying to bait me
out here. Luke in the chat. So if you
want to join in with Jaffen and become a
Patreon or or a moist slug and join in
as a chat and they distract us while we
record. what other otherwise would be an
impeccable podcast if not for these
these these desperate little individual
these leeches who you know trying to
drain our
drain our attention yeah
drain our attention
you know vile human beings who pay to
watch this anyway um Luke's trying to
George Pet just said oh that's what we
do but Luke's Luke's just said mad the
flav used to roast me for still liking
Bellingham and Jim for following Ez but
yet still in love with Kane I'm not in
love with Kane Kane, I don't care what
happens with Kane. I don't care unless
he comes back. Then I'm like, "Oh, come
on. Come back today."
Do you think he'll come back? You
presume he'd come back? I I generally
presume he he'd come back.
I can't imagine him doing it any if he's
going to break the record, he's got to
break it with us. I think the fact that
Daniel Levy isn't there anymore is a big
thing because you remember Daniel Levy
stole his career.
I mean, just fine, but yeah, I know what
you mean,
James. there. We know the reason why
he's disrespected in the way that he is
where to this day he doesn't get the
credit he deserves.
18 goals in 10 games or something
mental. I heard on the radio earlier
there's a reason why I tell you this.
I'm not proud of this James
we we stole his career. We sapped every
tiny little bit out of him and he wanted
to leave. We wouldn't let him.
We wouldn't let him. He was trapped in
that six year contract to [ __ ] ages.
Halfway through it he wanted out James.
He was going please let me leave. Look
at what I've given you. And You ever
know the truth about that? Was halfway
through you think he was he wanted out?
We know that that he did because that's
when he did the interview with
Okay. And you think I was right right?
Well, he said I think 100 million pound
would be the right fee for me and we
were like [ __ ] shut
you shut your mouth.
Yeah. And you keep scoring goals for
Spurs.
Gobling up the goals.
Yeah.
He loves goals, doesn't he? [ __ ]
He loves goals.
Yeah.
Like you know like there was a bit of a
dig on Shira from Keane. say he was a
bit he was a bit nasty as a player.
I don't think Kane's Kane's not Kane's a
bit cheeky in the He's a bit sly.
Yeah, he loves drawing a foul.
He loves draw, but he's never distracted
from his main aim. He's just chewing on
some lovely goals.
Just chomping on goals. Just eating
more. Just gave me the goal.
He loves it. Maybe that's why he wanted
to go to B. Maybe that was it. It's not
about
It's about career goals. It's not about
Premier League goals and he just loves
he [ __ ] lo He loves Is there a
footballer who loves something more
than Harry Kane loves girls
will because Harry Kane is just never he
is not satiated. He is never ever ever
ever satiated. Goals are pop chips to
him. He's just like whacking them in his
mouth. You cannot cannot get away from
the crunch.
Um
um
I'm trying to think.
Everything I came up with in my brain
was stuff I can't really say. So
I see I thought um
Lampard loved the shot. Loved the shot,
didn't he?
Yeah. I was listening. Yeah,
maybe um who loves a tackle. People
don't allow tackle anymore. Palino. You
say Palinino.
Richard Dunn loved loved a header.
Gobble up a little header.
What's the Pope? Loves a corner. Can't
can't keep away from them. Anyway, um
just on the patron thing quickly because
this made me laugh. Shan Bahangal
said seven eight years to eight years as
a proud dry slug until last night when I
dreamt that I was filling in the Jaffen
patron form. Not lifting the
championship trophy for my beloved CV.
Not climbing Everest. Just ticking boxes
online. It's the driest dream ever. And
maybe a damning indictment of a life
slowly being consumed by screens and AI
slop. But it worked. I finally gone
moisty. Moral of the story, inception is
the way to the dry slugs. Good.
It isn't. It's never too late.
Everybody, if you like the idea of
giving us money, just go ahead with it.
What this screams to me
is the the irony of
having the driest dream ever related to
being a moist slug, right? Has has led
you to the promised land of not being
dry anymore. And thus being a moisty is
inevitable. So really, you're just
slowing down the inevitable, which is
pointless. So become a moisty. The
link's in the description.
Job is done.
Click the link.
Yeah, get yourself.
I'm just gonna take this moment to bring
us back on track a little bit here, Jim.
I do want talk about Liverpool
struggling.
Yeah, let's talk about that. I'd love to
talk about that. But I want to talk
about Coventry City.
Hey, Lampard done a good job. And
because of that, I just you just think
like what where where's Coventry
situated? Sort of Midlands. Sort of
Midlands.
Yeah. 10 minutes outside of uh
Birmingham. Um, and you know, look at
all the money Birmingham City has spent.
Commentary ain't been able to do that.
Third in the league, aren't they?
Just a well-run football club that don't
lose games. And Birmingham have lost
two. All the money they've spent.
We're only two points off him. So
yeah, early days. Early days.
Two. We could go above them tonight.
I just like the idea that every
Lampard people have been [ __ ] on
Lampard as a manager. Shouldn't have got
the Everton job. Shouldn't have got the
Chelsea job. Inexperienced. Derby was he
was the reason he got Derby up was
because Mason Mount and Tamori played
for him. They had Harry Wilson as well
up top. They were too good not to
perform to that degree. And then he's
gone in at Coventry who were second
bottom of the league when he took over
and they're flying. So I want to say
let's give him his flowers.
Yeah.
And let's really look at the failings of
Birmingham despite spending all the
money.
I mean he came into a good squad. I will
say that he's taken off of Mark Robbins
who'd like put together a brilliant
squad.
Very true. and only two points ahead of
us and they beat 7-1. So, who's really
on the ascendancy here?
Indeed.
Well,
let's talk about Liverpool then.
Yes, let's do it. Yeah, because
then I'm confused. Flav,
they are they're good, but are they
good?
Cuz backto-back defeats Chelsea at the
weekend. Oh, do you know what was
mental? I just went to Tesco's an hour
ago. Guess who I bumped into? I
literally bumped my trolley into him and
he looked at me like he thought I was
doing it to rile him up.
You'll never guess. So I'll tell you.
Gacho,
what?
Yeah, I just bumped into guy cuz he's at
Chelsea. So they're all like live around
kind of this way.
Did you know that?
Transfer. Yeah, it was quite
he was with his Yeah, he was with with
his mom doing the shop doing the big
shop.
You you you bumped into Gacho. literally
bumped into Gacha and he looked he
stared at me and I was like I don't know
if he was like just not best pleased
because I bumped into him.
Yeah, he needs his legs for football.
Yeah,
I'm not bumped into him. I bump into his
trolley.
Ah, who how disguised was he?
He had a he had a hat and a hood.
Yeah, I was going to say you need that.
But it was 20° today in London. So was
he hot?
Uh he had shorts on as well. So it's not
I mean it wasn't too hot.
I I cannot understand that from Chelsea.
I really don't understand it. I know if
there there's a PSR
um you know spending opportunity or or
or advantage by selling Mke and then
buying Ganachio because you can spread
it over 5 years or whatever it might be
whereas 52 million pound on the books is
immediate but Mke in my opinion I'm
[ __ ] sick of talking positively about
Arsenal's players but I was talking
about good how good Maker was when he
was at Chelsea and I was really confused
about all Arsenal fans were going no
he's no good the what are are you
seeing? Do you even [ __ ] watch
football? The kid is good.
How there was there was close to
protests about this signing. It was
pathetic.
This kid is mustard and he's he's he is
and he will have twice the career of
Garnacho. So, how they sold him and
brought in and and I appreciate they
played on on typically on different
wings, but it did feel like a light for
light replacement. And I just for me
is twice as good.
That's interesting. I think well I chat
to Cabs yesterday did the Spotify pod
and I I think we didn't totally drill
down on it but I I definitely think
there's something in
well I this sounds obvious but like the
second season of a player like the first
season everyone's deciding if you're
rubbish or not and you kind of almost
just need to get through that first
performance or first season
and in that second season when you feel
you know you got the rhythm of the
league you got the understanding of the
pace of the league the physicality of
the league where you live, how long your
big shop takes, all those things. When
you've done all those things in the
second year, like Nicholas Madson, who
on this podcast, I I don't think I said
his name. I might have said his name. I
think it's one of the first times I've
gone out and out and go like, "This lad
is rubbish last year on the pod." Cuz he
was he was awful for us, right?
He's he's really, really, really found
his feet for us. And I feel like that's
that can often be the case for so many
play like Caluri for example like you
know there's probably other things at
play but like you know moving to a new
like we forget about all those other
things and with Chelsea you've just got
to a place of rhythm I would say with a
group there
and then you've got and then you've just
brought in two new wingers and got rid
of one like you know you sort of kind of
lost some of that by by changing that in
what is a really quite key area of the
pitch. I I really like Pedro Netto, but
like you're going to have to change it
about at different times. So, I think
it's one where like Gacho probably will
come good. I'm guessing I don't like who
knows, right? Gittens as as well is
obviously very talented, but like it's
going to take them a year. So, you've
actually kind of g you they need to like
embed
into that team because it's young
enough. you need them to sort of know
each other, become accountable for each
other, understand each other, like and
and I think that's the that's the thing
with Liverpool
that I wondered at the start of the
season with all these new players coming
in is this. It's the chemistry thing.
It's such it's so clearly a thing for
me.
And did Ann Arnold Swat did not feel
like he did he want to change the way
they played? I don't know the answers to
these because I was trying to I was
speaking to um our mutual friend Dan
Cook. I do a podcast with him called
Football Between the Lines.
So many great podcasts to enjoy, isn't
there?
Yes, almost too many, Jim. But we've all
got to make hayw.
All right, enough podcast there. No
more. Um but yeah, we we were talking
about this and obviously he was ecstatic
the fact that Palace, you know, you
talked about teams are they good and who
is fundamentally good? Palace are
fundamentally good at at the moment. Um,
but I was asking them to try and break
down what was going wrong with Liverpool
like what what was it? Why did you find
it so easy to get at them defensively?
Whereas last season they were pretty
imperious for large parts of it. You
know, they were almost criticized to
some degree of being solid and a
functional Liverpool side. the early
season Liverpool were picking up wins,
you know, by one or two goal margins and
putting them in an incredible position
to win the league by being functional.
And I also called Chris Payjack to try
and find out
right
what was I do that
anyone you need to call to find out
what's going on at Liverpool, he will
give you
Chris
a nutshell in five minutes. It's
beautiful.
Yeah,
but this was this was a couple of weeks
back to be fair. So he he'd been on
holiday, so he didn't give me a great
deal. But the the the fact is is that
it's hard to pin down why they're not
firing. Now some Liverpool fans will go
out there and go, "Hang on a second. We
won five games on the B." Was it five
games? Four game. Five games on the
bounce.
Who? Liverpool.
Late goals. Yeah, late goals. Was five.
Yeah. Um
and you know, things are going well.
Late goals are a sign of champions.
Good. Uh,
did you just press that button then?
Yeah.
I didn't think you'd hear it. So, I was
trying to just sneak it in there.
Yeah, I did. I did hear it.
Sorry about the browser.
I've totally derailed you there. My bad.
Yeah, you have. Sorry, mate. Uh, why am
I apologizing? You derailed me. The the
Where was I?
You asked Chris Pjack. What's What's
going on?
No, no, no, no. So, so, so, so the
discussion was being had that that that
is this Liverpool side good at the
moment
or is their position at the top of legal
force one and the way we kind of come to
the conclusion was we looked at the
expected points table that we discussed
last week.
Yeah.
And they should be eighth based on
expected points which doesn't you know
and and I I don't want this to be true
cuz Spurs should be something like 13th.
M
um but there were Liverpool fans kicking
back a little bit at us at that
conversation saying you know we're
winning games you know don't don't you
worry about it but there's something not
right and I want and my qu my question
is and I'd love Liverpool fans to answer
this it's not I just don't know the
answer and I want to get to it is is it
Anna slot changing the way Liverpool
play to make them more exciting you know
bought in really lovely players like
Florianz I know he started horrendously
and it's become a story and the pressure
will continue to grow around him. But
you have to get that right if you spend
that kind of money. But you put in Isak
who started brilliantly, you know, you
know, KZA having a role that we we
thought he'd probably be dismissed and
he's he's becoming an important. So
second season
second season. Exactly. Uh and you got
the best six in the league in Gravenb.
People would might argue or you might
you might say that there's another club
in in North London that might have that,
but
Benenko,
not him.
The uh uh Yeah. So, so I just I just
want to know what what's going on
because right now they're not good.
Right now they are underperforming and
that level of expenditure regardless of
how much you recouped that's not how the
narrative is spun in football media.
It's how much do you spend
it just means that you you expect more
and maybe they will come good. You know
the odds for the champions them winning
it haven't changed. They're still
favorites.
Even though they got beat by Galatas
last night,
they expect more.
Uh that I think that is part of it. Like
when you spend that kind of money, you
go, "All right, instant results. Off you
go, boys." And that's like that's what
I've been saying like it does not it
will take a minute. This season it is
trickier. A few thoughts, right? One,
the expected points thing. One thing I
would chuck out there, right, Liverpool,
and I'm not saying this is right or
wrong, but I'm saying it maybe it's it's
um it's a crack in the expected points
table
is
if you get a couple of goals up, you
then maybe chill out a bit in a game and
that can and what we have seen with
Liverpool is that they go to up and then
they haven't been able to like shut it
out in the same way they, you know, like
would that would that have been the same
if it had been would their expected
points somehow actually be somewhat
higher if they were if the game was
tighter and they're going and going and
going at them whereas once they're two
goals up they just stop.
Yeah. Yeah.
So games plays a part in it. That's one
thing. Uh yeah like the this the players
that have been bought
have been bought for the next five. It's
about the next six seven years not about
this year. It's almost because they've
won the league. It's almost difficult,
more difficult than the fact that
they've won the league in a way.
Like they would for the world, but the
expectation is through the roof now
because they've won the league and you
expect them to get better than the team
they had last year and it might be
better. The more possibilities, the
ceiling might be higher, but like you
say, Jim, it could be two or three years
until you see it. I think that also like
the balance the balance thing is
somewhat of an issue
because
the this team's not going to be Salah's
team in two years time. It's going to be
Vertz's team. I know he's had a
difficult start, but
yeah,
I was watching that
I was watching the positions he was
getting. His movement is really clever.
The only thing he maybe does a little
bit too much is he comes a little bit
too close to the ball at times, but that
can actually be beneficial um if you get
it right. And he technically generally
does get it right. I in the Galatas
game. It was a bad game, but if I
watched I was interested because we're
going to be we're never going to do a
video on Verts and like you know why why
is he struggling a little bit. So I
started to like do a bit of digging and
I looked at all of the his passes and he
gets he gets into lovely positions, gets
the ball, affects the sort of speed of
the game a little bit, gets the defi the
defense sort of um
sort of nervous and does affect the
game. But I think I watched about 25
passes from his game against Galatessay
and I don't I think he gave the ball
away once
but but in about 15 of those passes the
person who he passed to they gave the
ball away.
Yeah. And there when he got the ball in
certain central areas instead of wide
areas, I think one of the times he gave
the ball away or a couple of times he
was quite quite far out wide. When he
got the ball in those kind of central
areas and and they played it to him at
the right time, he he affected the game
was really neat. There's one bit where
he got it before ech or yeah played it
eert got it back off him. Salah had
gone. Oh, it's Frim Pong had gone and
Vertz played this beautiful pass and a
few of the and the other passes that he
was giving the ball away. They were
actually good passes and and difficult
passes.
James, you need to release this video
now, not in a week. I'm thinking about
it. I should do this video. Release it
now.
Okay.
Do you know what the Liverpool fans need
to hear this? They need to hear someone
saying this. This is I'm not saying play
the game here, Jim, but play the [ __ ]
game. This is exactly what you need to
do.
We play the game. Play the game. You got
to do it right. We we we've got a I I
did a um I did a whole thing on Palace
and and Liverpool. I watched that whole
game. Um we've got this like with the
Premier League, we've got this tactical
cam now and it's just it's so good, so
useful. And uh and anyway, but yeah, but
I did I I sort of smashed through a
video which could have put on the on in
the shed, but we wanted to like really
really edit it and make the point. So,
we're taking we we decid that's a
decision we've made as a team recently
is though. It's not about being first.
It's about like being of a high level.
So, we will we'll do that. Um, but yeah,
I the to give away that video a little
bit. The problem is not verts.
The problem is not verts for me. It's
Liverpool fans.
It's Liverpool fans.
Yes.
It's the It's the uh It's the GA
brigade, the double, you know, it's the
fact it's the price tag. Like, it's all
those things. He is a little bit you
think you know he's thinking maybe a
little bit too much at times and other
players are not always on his wavelength
and that he hasn't I don't think he's
really really really been given the keys
just yet
but
it's so good that you're you're doing
this Jim right this is what why you you
know you have the respect within the
industry that you do have and people
like you really understand the game
because I had lunch with my dad earlier
and he went
good creator in his own right. Yeah,
just ain't good enough, is he, girl? I
mean, what do you mean, Dan?
Ain't got it.
Anyone can play in the German league.
Anyone.
And that was the sum total of why he
won't make it in the Premier League. So,
there you go.
Yeah, man. I I I think wait. But like
the only thing is, you know, if a player
sort of crumbles in these scenarios, but
also it's about getting players in the
positions they want to be and then
having the players around him once he
gets it.
And that's the same for a lot of these
teams. And the ones that do it the
quickest will will be the most
successful. The problem you've got with
Liverpool, there's too many of them. I
that's that's I don't think I'm
struggling with
I'm struggling with that team in terms
of all of the all of those players all
together. That's that's the thing I'm
when I'm watching them, it doesn't feel
like it has that flow. And I don't think
I think not made a mistake, but I do
think it's maybe hurting them a little
bit selling Lewis Diaz.
Yeah. Yeah, potentially. But you kind of
have to get if they're going to outlay
it, they've got to find money back. And
that kind of money from Bayern Munich is
insane, isn't it? Because,
you know, they just pay massive inflated
price. It's idiot tax really when you're
selling to Bayern Munich. But um the the
other issue, Jamir, is they have to
stack their squad because everyone
around them is stacking their squad.
Yeah.
You can make five subs in the Premier
League now. Um your club is expected and
Liverpool's expected to challenge on
four fronts, which is impossible to do
if you haven't got a big squad. So, they
they've done the right thing. They've
improved, you would say, on paper, the
squad they had last season.
It's just going to take a lot a little
bit more time for it to click and gel.
And Anna Slott's a great manager.
He'll get it right. It just isn't
working right now as all.
Yeah, it's going to take it takes the
the chemistry takes time, I think. And
he has been changing it quite a lot.
Uh and you've had, you know, like Sosa
playing at right back or playing in
midfield, he's been playing in lots of
different positions. So Bos, you know,
he'll do a job there at times, but on
occasion it'll also maybe backfire a
touch, but there might be games where it
actually is quite useful as well when
you're chasing it. The one thing I did
want to chuck out there.
Yeah.
Would
Liverpool have a sort of better
balance maybe if they'd not sold Lewis
Diaz
and they'd not bought Isach, but they'd
bought Voltoard instead. Oh.
Oh, I think I've just come, Jim.
Do you know what I mean? Like status
wise, I think you would have had
Echk and Voltoas battling out kind of
kind of similar players in certain areas
that they want to be in. You'd still
have that zip and pace from
on the left hand side of Diaz and
and maybe I don't know if maybe verts
wouldn't totally work as well. I don't
know. Uh
the answer in the short term is perhaps.
The answer in the long term is no. Isak
is the it could be but very good point.
So they have to they have to do it and
and and if the opportunity to buy him is
there you know you look at Gawkarez who
looks like a bumbling idiot at times
and and what they could have had with
ESAC if they were willing to go that far
or if they had the financial
capabilities of doing it.
Do you think if and just to sort of like
copy and paste all these signings if do
you think I I think everyone's being
quite patient with Liverpool really
they're kind of going it will come good
it will come good because you got too
much quality there if those players had
been bought by
Man United or Arsenal or Chelsea do you
think there'd be that same patience?
No. Do you think people getting angry
quick? desperately after maybe not
patience you would suggest you would
suggest comes from the fan base patience
is what you expect from your own fan
base it's where scrutiny from the wider
footballing community would harsh you
think
yeah probably not like people were
desperate for cockaress to be terrible
it's weird it was like this hate watch
universal hate watch that everybody was
involved in and it was a beautiful
moment like you know this is like
cuz the funny thing is Liverpool top
Liverpool like we just had this
conversation like They're they like
they're like they're a bit off, aren't
they? You still you know it's still
edible. Like they're top of the league.
They are top of the league.
Yeah. Interestingly, you've got you know
Oh, sorry. Can we Can you just Is that
Can people see this league? Just scroll
down a second. Scroll down. Scroll.
Scroll down.
Let me show the people.
Scroll down. Scroll down a second.
Okay.
Scroll down.
Scroll down
to the bottom. Yeah. I want to see. Oh,
he's down there. That's some big teams
down there. People see this. Can they
Jim?
Uh, they're about to. Here you go.
All right. There's some uh there's big
teams down there. There's Ajax down
there. Jesus Christ.
Down there.
Monaco. Good side.
Mhm.
Athletic club. Bill B. Yeah. Fair
enough. PSV. Napoli. Napoli. Syria are
winners. Napoli
down there. That's interesting. That's
interesting. Then
Oh, Dortmund. Juventus in midfield in
the mid table. That's that's good. Just
scroll up a bit. Oh, scroll up a bit.
It's got a bit my ankles. Jim, what is
that,
mate? This comes out tomorrow.
That's weird.
Oh, does it? [ __ ]
It's going to come out tomorrow and
you're going to be like mid table at
this point.
All right. Oh, there we go.
Hey, look. You got to go early.
It's like go early. I didn't realize.
Didn't realize him. Didn't realize. One
must beware hub. Bodo glimpmp.
Probably should have won that.
Buddha glimp. Bod limp. Uh, sorry. I you
know I I uh was faced by I got a I got
tagged in a tweet and I was like I saw
this
and um it was an undercover an lover
Spurs fan an lover.
Yeah.
I I I don't even remember the point I
would have made. I think it was
something to do with XG and and an not
winning the XG battle.
I do remember you making that point.
Yeah. And Thomas Frank has not been
winning the XG battle.
I mean we've No.
No.
and and I got sort of you know I got uh
informed on that which is fine.
Um
is this so there there is this I'd let
people I'll let people behind the
curtain of what's happening in the
Tottenham fan base.
What's the seed of doubt with Tottenham?
That's what I wanted to ask.
I can ask I can answer that question but
before that um there is a clutch a cabal
a clan a cult of
an evangelists
who are waiting for Frank to fail and I
don't know if they're Australians
I don't know if they're Spurs fans I
don't know who they are because they
don't they never say who I am a
Tottenham fan season ticket holder for
25 years they never say that they've
just lurking in the shadows waiting for
this to fail in some degree. So, um
yeah. Uh so that's probably why you
received that message. What the what did
you say? What was the question about the
the
doubt?
Most managers leave their job. don't
know if you're aware of this. And what
what I see a lot of time is not the not
the crazy amount of independent thought
like there's just like well this has
been said so off we go and it gets
bigger and bigger and bigger.
Um and with uh with uh Thomas Frank who
uh who I thought start you know has
started the season pretty well in terms
of picking up points and stuff.
Lost one lost one go.
Yeah. Beat Man City obviously. Uh yeah.
What? Um, obviously the the army the
Frank out army is going to be like
wildly minimal right now, but
No, it's not an army. It's like a
militia. I would say it's a group of 20
or 30 uh
what do you call them?
Well, they're just not having it.
No, there's some people there. No, look,
no one's not having it. I just think
that people don't have patience and want
everything to be fixed right now. Now
the criticisms of an sorry Jesus Thomas
Frank I spent two years talking about
the criticisms of anger that's why that
just fell out of my mouth. um Thomas
Frank is that the the attacking aspect
of our players is
it's not looking great, right? We don't
look very dangerous when we're playing
forward,
right?
And there's a couple of reasons why that
might be, right? You got Javi Simmons
who bought in and has been played off
the left and you know eventually will
play in the 10. It's completely relying
on him being very good for Tottenham and
for good reason. you know, there's big
money coming and and so we should be
relying on him. Um, but what Frank's
decided to do for a large proportion of
his time as manager is have three
midfielders that are relatively similar.
Certainly two. So if you got Pinia
holding and tackling and destroying,
your 10 is either Beraval or Paps are.
Yeah.
And neither of those are tens.
They're not dancy 10, are they?
No, they're not. But they're not
effective in attack tens either. They
are defensive tens if if that isn't even
a thing. I don't think
Yeah. Burg's an eight, isn't he? Really?
Sort of like a
Yeah. Yeah. Pretty, isn't he?
Yeah. He's a little blonde [ __ ]
Yeah. Yeah. I don't like blondes. But
there's something about him.
Yeah. And Kinsky, two little blonde
[ __ ] we got. They're both class. But
no, the um but but my point is is that
you need when we're going forward to
have a technical 10. The A 10 who's
gonna
is going to What is that music?
You can.
Isn't it me? I
think it's you. It
No, it's not my All right. Well, I can
go with the music if you like.
My music stopped. You're having a rave.
What's going on?
Yeah, it's your music. Is it me?
Um
yeah, it was you. Anyway, [ __ ] you.
That's twice you derailed me in the
first single episode.
Uh you need you need we're not looking
fluent because we don't have the the the
personnel to play fluent football at the
moment. But what Frank's done is come in
and he's solidified us in the way that
we would get battered every week. It
never feels like we're going to get
battered. The frustration comes from
when watching Spurs is our lack of
cutting edge going forward, but it will
come. And it it's it's no surprise that
we were desperate to sign Zabinho from
Manchester City because he would have
offered that Stardust on the left hand
side, that player who can unlock a
defense, you can go past a player and
Yes. So, um, so that's where the
frustration comes. But we don't have to
worry about that. It's fine. This is a
project that's going to be two or three
years in the making. It's not win
immediately, win now. We are third in
the league in the Premier League. Yeah,
I was just going to say well a couple of
things. First of all, there's five teams
that have scored over 10 goals in double
digits in terms of scoring goals. You
are one of them. Second thing, you've
got the third best goal difference in
the league.
Yeah.
Okay. So, I think it's just a bit more
better than this and that's good, isn't
it?
It's a bit more regimented, isn't it?
Like
Yeah. It's just not as it's not as free
flowing as people want. And I get that
you want that. You pay a lot of money to
go and watch your team play, but it will
come. I hope it comes. But right now,
you got to think positively about the
situation, find ourselves.
And last bit of football chat before we
get into the other bits and pieces is uh
I've written Man United must win,
to save his job Sunday.
I have no I I have no respect
for Manchester United at all. It's all
out the window for me, Jim. Don't I
respect the people I know who follow
Manchester United. I respect them and I
feel for them. I'm thinking about Adam
Makola specifically when I say this.
This way, didn't he?
There was a clip of him after the
Arsenal game saying I' I'd seen it. He
said he'd seen after the Arsenal games
he went I know people are angry but I
seen it. He's like I've seen we're going
to be all right.
sustain the stuff.
But um
but that what is he still doing there,
Jim? What is he doing there? Why is he
still there?
What is literally talking himself out of
a [ __ ] job after every loss saying I
won't change. I won't. And I've heard
that before, by the way, of that
rhetoric, that dogmatism. But it's like
it this isn't working. Like someone
needs to grab him by the ears and go,
"It isn't working, Amarim.
Change. [ __ ] change or you'll be
gone." And why Racul hasn't gone.
All right. Yeah, we probably we've made
a mistake.
Yeah,
we uh we should probably just get rid of
him. Like even if it's like we haven't
got a manager lined up or and I hate to
say it because I don't want to see
Palace lose Glasnar because it's great
to see a club that would is middling to
lowlevel Premier League in terms of
their expectations but really be
competitive beat Liverpool for example
18 games unbeaten
that's really good I don't want to see
him go to Man United and Man United do
well I don't want that but if you're
Rackcliffe you're going right we have
[ __ ] up we can fix this immediately
and they just he is just like that the
problems aren't amorim the problem right
now is amarim but that that problem of
Manchester United doesn't go away for
Manchester United fans it begins and
ends with the Glazers and then Jim
Ratcliffe is right in the middle of it
like a little festering virus
wow
uh
the uh some of the guys here Connor says
is Man United fan I would guess he said
we won't beat Sunderland we can't beat
anyone.
You mean Chelsea?
Um,
yeah. Amazing. And
you like Sunderland so far, Jim?
Yeah. We got the Premier League our
Premier League video this week is on
Sunderland.
Um, and how they're they're so young.
It's cra like all the all the
the average age.
Yeah. All the sort of principles that
you would think. Get players in who know
the league, you know, get some
experience in there. guys have been
there, done it, blah blah blah. Even the
manager like, "Nope, none of that. We're
going to play this way." And they've got
some really good signings and and
they're platforming Granite Jacquer in a
way that's making him thrive and and
they're doing really well.
Jim, can I um can can if there's ever a
a piece of evidence
that you might need if you were to
differentiate
your your your career path and mine,
right?
it would be that I had to Google after
watching the Nottingham Forest versus
Sunderland game
who the Sunderland manager was and
I struggled to remember his name for a
while as well. It's fine.
I But Jim, I was looking at him. I was
like, who is who is that?
Yeah.
What is
you don't see his face much?
I always think that's interesting. So,
like with YouTube, you do a lot of uh
you do a lot, you know, do a lot of
thumbnails, right? And it's always
interesting to think like what's the
face? Who's the face of the club? And
for Sunderland, it's Granjaka. It's not
it's not Reggie Lee. J. Sometimes it's
the manager. Sometimes it's a
Sometimes it's a certain player. We
could play that game.
Face of the club. Ready?
You just just give me a name.
I'll start at the top.
Liverpool.
First name. First name. Think of huh?
Slot. Slot. Slot.
Arsenal.
Rice.
Oh, Palace. Glasgnner,
Tottenham,
Frank.
Yeah. Sunderland,
Jaca.
Yeah. Bournemouth,
areola,
Man City,
Pep,
Chelsea.
Oh,
it's Mesa.
You think Palmer for me? Everton.
Palmer. No, it is Palmer. It is Palmer.
It is Palmer.
Everton.
Uh, Everton. Um, Greish at the moment,
but Mo
Brighton.
Hersler for me.
Yeah, fair
silver.
Silva. Yeah,
silver
leads
Parker because he'll be the reason why
they
Anton Stack I've got my Bren Brenford
still Frank
Henderson for me still Frank
Man United
Rashford.
No, no, for me it's Rackcliffe and it
always will be.
Really think Rackcliffe first.
Yeah. Not not for good things, for for
bad things.
Interesting.
Newcastle
Ultima.
Who do I think for Bruno? I think
Aston Villa
obviously Emory, but on the pitch, who
do I think of first? Watkins.
Yeah.
Forest.
Marinakis.
Yeah.
Burnley.
Estee. Esteev.
Yeah. You like him, don't you? Parker
for me. West Ham, Bowen,
Brady,
and Wolves.
I don't care.
Just don't give a [ __ ]
Could be anyone. Couldn't Couldn't care.
Do you know just to be transparent, I I
look I I wanted to get this bit off the
ground. So, I looked at the bottom of
the thing and I saw wolves and I went,
"If you go back, you wind back." Okay,
let's start at the top.
Could kill us.
Uh, Aras is the name I think of.
Brilliant. Uh, okay. So,
uh, celebration.
Oh, yeah. Before we move on, Ollie H
coming up with a belter and he knows the
answer already.
Says Karen Brady Flav would you
100%.
Yeah. You ready?
Strong woman.
Strong. Like I say, borderline racist.
Yeah. You know, my place a bit posh
maybe
financially dominate me. That's Yeah.
Can dominate you in and out of the
bedroom
everywhere.
Yeah. Um interesting.
Uh Connor Rally said for Wolves the
Portugal flag. It kind of is that, isn't
it?
Portugal.
Wait, they have been served by the
nation of Portugal in a way that no
other club has outside of Portugal.
Yeah. So, celebration police cuz we were
talking about the shirt being taken off.
Do you remember that an hour ago? Um, I
just did want to get your How did you
feel about Pellini taking his shirt off
after getting the equalizer against a
team that you know nothing about in
Wolves? Were you okay with it?
Uh, I mean I So, I was so angry at that
point that I didn't move when we scored
that goal. In fact, I was I was just
furious with Tottenham. I was furious
with Thomas Frank. I was furious with
everybody. Um, so I don't look like [ __ ]
anyone who wants to go
get [ __ ] man. Let him celebrate. If
people want to go mental celebrate,
that's what the point of this [ __ ]
sport is, James, is to explode in
emotion. All the tactics, all the money
spent on players, the the ticket price
that gets in, the shitty food or great
food in some instance that you're eating
at certain sta stadiums, everything is
about that moment when the ball goes in
the net, it should be anyway. And so if
that moment in causes you as a player or
as a fan to lose yourself, then
why would you want to take that away?
unless it's to get one over on your on
your rivals. But but fundamentally, it's
the most important part of of football.
It's the only thing that should matter.
You just got so many bellins that are
putting themselves in the way of the
ball being struck and the ball going
into the net and the reaction to it.
They need to get a life, Jim. I don't
like it. I don't accept it.
Perfect. I couldn't agree more. Uh Paul
Casey, do you remember Paul at the start
of the pod? He didn't never read his
comment out. He said this. Uh taking
your shirt off should mean something. I
don't want shirts to be taken off for
any big standard co goal. That doesn't
make sense. Big standard goal.
I want it taken off for massive late
winning goals where the player says,
"Book me. I don't care." Players taking
their shot off for an 86th minute third
round League Cup winner against a team
38 league places below them when the
goal itself was a six-y open goal.
Should be grounds for a straight red.
Never mind a second yellow.
Big Willie agrees. As a Liverpool fan, I
like the rule because you should only
take a shirt off for a goal if it's
worth getting a yellow card for. You
should only take your top off for a late
winner against rivals in and in cup
finals. [ __ ] off.
No, because that
So what? So a QBR player can never ever
ever ever take his shirt off unless it's
against a rival. You you just narrowed
it down to the privilege in that it can
only be when we're in our win our cup
finals, which we're in four every
season. Shut up, Big Willie.
Yeah, big Willie. Um,
my this is the point is is that when
when a player scores a goal, if they're
instant reaction is that they're so
excited that they want to take the show
off and show their ripped torso, who am
I to disagree? Absolutely.
Um, Paul Casey came back later in his
session watching Jaffen and uh he gave
us an analogy. He said, "Taking your
shirt off to celebrate is like a
lunchtime pint. Part of it allure is
that you know you shouldn't do it but do
it anyway.
Yeah, that's good work, Paul. You
redeemed yourself.
Flav's pallet. This next bit's called.
Oh, by the way, any celebration police
bits or any celebration stories? Any
really nourishing celebration stories? I
would love to hear moments where you got
to tr like celebrate in whatever way
that is. Not taking his top off or
anything like that. So, just a moment of
celebration that's really lovely and
smug and funny. Get that in the
comments. Um, Flav's palette. Uh Joe
Joseph Kapowi said, "Flav's favorite
milk is red top."
Check his hard drive.
It's not my favorite. Semi skims is
everybody's favorite, isn't it? Oh,
okay. Backtracking on that. I thought
you said you like the red top.
You think I'm buy I No, I can't remember
what the point I was making, but no one
was buying red top.
Okay.
No, I said Oh, red. Hang on a second.
Red top is skimmed, right?
Yeah.
Oh, I see. Yeah, I like skimmed milk and
tea. Yeah, if I have milk at all.
Why?
Sorry, I did. I did say that.
Why? Just I just wanted
It's too much fat. It's too It's too
much fat in it. It's too much milkiness.
I don't want my tea to taste milky. It
needs to taste the tea. I want to taste
the tea in the tea bag.
Your palette fascinates me.
Well,
I just like the sort of bitterness. I
like the the bitter. I like
What are your favorite? Do So, do you do
you like what do you like most? Salty,
creamy, crunchy, bitter, sour, spicy.
Amami. Amami.
Yeah.
Okay.
I mean, you you should be up for that.
You're You've married into Amami.
Yeah.
Well, that's the basis of their mommy.
Um,
that's her name. I know that. I know.
Uh, new bit. I really like this. I
really, really love this. Please, please
put more in and and start with the
sentence. Why did I say that? Why did I
say that?
Chris Barker
that. Sorry, that's my favorite one. So,
I'll read the other one first. This the
second one. I was laughing for ages. I
don't know why it tickled me. Anyway,
plague boy said, "Why did I say that
moment? I was watching a I was watching
a UFC match uh when completely
unprompted." The commentator said, "Both
fighters having dealt with custody
battles for their children while the
fighters are beating the [ __ ] out of
each other." Co just come through the
door, so I'm not swearing now. There
wasn't even a lull in the fight.
said play.
I think I've seen that clip before. It
doesn't make any sense.
That's really funny. This baby giggle.
Chris Parker. Why did I say that? I was
at a party when I was about 16. There
was a girl that I'd flirted with a lot,
but mainly online. At the end of the
party, everyone was loitering around the
front of the house. The girl comes up to
me and asked if I would walk her home,
which to which I replied,
Well, how far is it?
It's a fair Well, how far is it?
It's a fair question.
Would you um Would you like to take me
home? Well, how far is it?
Yeah. Not the you know, how far would
you work? How far would
How far would you would you would you be
willing to walk
in that moment? If she said it's three
miles away, are you willing in in in the
hope that that you would, you know,
eventually get your end away?
Yeah. Is that negging or how far is it?
I mean, maybe you said the right way,
you might get away with it, but like
kind of ruined the moment there, mate.
And he said, "How far is he?" He went,
"I knew it was close. I don't know why I
said it." She walked away and nothing
ever happened between us. Dawn on me
later that night. The opportunity had
spurned and still bothers me to this
day. Brilliant. more of those kind of
things, please.
Uh, and last one. Oh, no. Got a couple.
This isn't normal. Pasta Bof said, "I
don't know if this could be a bit, but I
thought it could be funny to hear things
that people have always had in their
house and one day just realized this
isn't normal."
Um, the reason I find it funny is like
you see it on thumbnails all the time.
We we we've done it a few times where
you like you have a bit of text on the
thumbnail and and it's this isn't
normal.
Yeah.
Um, okay. Minus the fact who could it
be?
All right, here we go. Minus the fact
that my mom regularly steals crockery
from Weather Spoons.
So much so that I that only a fraction
of our total table wear doesn't belong
to spoons.
Your mom's a thief. Are you
dinner plates, side plates, bowls, the
little baskets they bring out halumi
fries in, little dipping pots, all of
it. I realized a couple of days ago when
I was went to make cereal for breakfast
for the first time in ages, realizing we
no longer owned any cereal bowls, I
stared at the stack of those
unmistakable blue and white floral bowls
and just thought, "This isn't normal, is
it?"
Only
Yeah. I mean,
your mom
Your mom's a faith.
Your mom Your mom's a faith, mate.
It ain't great.
Yeah. Yeah, I mean there there was
things in my when I growing up, I grew
up in a bit of a weird house and um not
my dad's house, but my my mom's partner,
he he was into sort of um sort of you
know like I don't know like stars and
sort of astrology and that sort of
stuff.
So there was lots of weird bits and
pieces around the house and uh and there
was a puppet on on on top of on this
this puppet had hung there. It was like
a French trilicus do dummy.
Oh god, that's so scary.
It would h it was just put on, you know,
like um just next to where we hung the
coats and it would just sort of look
down and and and I would look at it and
I I wouldn't even look it. I was I would
walk past it with my head down for about
the first 10 years. It used to freak and
I'm like that's not normal having that
and that that isn't who why is the value
here? Not a piece of art. It's just
[ __ ]
That's quality. Uh so yeah, that uh
things that this isn't normal. Let us
know yours. Um if you want to provide
pictures as well, my DMs are open. Like
I'd love to see this puppet. I'd love to
see this picture of this puppet.
I'll never I'll never I'll never
You never looked at it, have you? Um
okay. This and last bit, the guy near
me. Uh you were talking about the guy
Oh, no. There was a guy like there's a
guy, one of our patrons who said about
it, he's got these two guys who stink.
And you said you said that they need to
talk to them and basically go look
stink.
Um
I found the dummy. I've literally found
a dummy.
You found the You found the puppet.
I found the puppet that was on.
I'll send it to you. Send it to on the
I'm so scared.
Yeah. However,
send me a link.
Yeah. All right.
Oh dear.
What's your Yeah, I tell we that'll be
the last thing we'll do. I'll just read
these out quickly. So, uh the guy near
me, Ash, uh says, "Uh, we've got a we've
got a got to do better here. Guy near
me. We go one nil down. We've got to do
better. Drawing at halftime. We've got
to do better. We managed to scrape a
late win. We pulled through in the end,
but we've got to be better. We've got to
do better." So, he's got to do better,
guy.
Uh
and this one. Oh, yeah. This is a Spurs.
Oh, it's Ben. Ben Spantum Walker.
Remember Ben Spantum Walker?
Yeah, of course.
Hello, mate. He said, "Football
characters, around my Spurs season
ticket, there's a guy who leaves five
minutes early every week." As he's
leaving, he looks in the general
direction of the crowd as he's going
down the stairs and shouts, "Clyide
about four times and puts his thumb up
and disappears into the concourse. We
all assume there's a Clyde somewhere,
but none of us are completely sure."
Interesting.
Uh, last football character, Harry. Uh,
the football character chat reminded me
of an older guy I sat next to for around
10 years at Goodison Park. My dad and I
referred to him as hit him. This came
from the fact that we only ever heard
him say around 10 words during the time
we sat there and this was loudly
screaming hit him or [ __ ] hit him
whenever the opposition had the ball for
any length of time. This would happen at
least once during a game for the first
four or five years. After COVID hit, hit
him became a bit more subdued and his
hit screams were reduced massively to
maybe three or four uh once every three
or four games. This made my dad and I
speculate whether something had happened
to hit him's private life. I only heard
him shout two other things at a game
over 10 years. This was once during a
game against Man City where he loudly
exclaimed, "Manchester, wank wank wank."
And once loudly shouted, "Fuck off
Fulham." whenever we were playing
Forest.
As a true football character, I I do I
did not know his name or anything about
him. In fact, I've never seen him at any
other place than that seat at Goodison
Park. As we left the ground in May, my
dad said that we'd probably never see
hit him again. A true loss. That is that
does that does scare me. Like the day
you got to move seats or if you know
like we there's no space for Co. If Co
wants to watch me and my dad, we got
figure that out. I don't really know
what to do.
Jim, did did this come from um when I
was talking about the ref at Spurs?
I thought we were talking about the guy
there's a guy who stinks. Oh, you spoke
about someone.
I can't remember.
Yeah, but there was another guy called
the ref at Spurs who um
I've just seen. Is that you?
Yeah, it could have been me, but no.
That is
all right. Let's move on to that.
Yeah, that was hung up. It was that in
that clothing as well with that red hair
and the
and it would hang hang above the stairs.
What?
Not not h hanging but like not it was
just placed there and I'm like it's one
of the most scary things.
That is horrific. Right, here we go.
Ready everyone?
Young Flav here.
What the That is just so grim. Imagine
that.
Yeah, it was there.
Who's making that? And imagine you're
making that. And they're going, "And
who's this for?" It's for kids. It's for
kids.
Yeah, it's for kids.
It's famous. This This thing This thing
was famous in the 80s when ventriloquist
dummies became popular. This was like
the go-to model for people to practice
on.
The go-to model. The hair.
Grim. So scary.
Got a sad note to end on. But uh there
we go.
Yeah.
Uh right, I'm off to go watch QPR.
Hopefully win again.
Come to us.
Can't boys.
Hang on a second, boys. It's uh it's QPR
versus
Oxford.
Oxford. Yeah. What? Beware
Will Lere say
a cheeky win. Cheeky win. And we
probably go into the
sh.
Be quiet. Be quiet. Whisper it. Right,
everyone, have a great uh rest of your
week and we'll be back next week. Speak
soon. Bye.