Right then people, welcome back to the
more James Orcot channel with me, Moore.
Let's talk about this England squad. Uh
Jude Bellingham has been left out.
That's the top headline, but actually
it's the subplots under that that I
think are far more I mean somewhat
confusing, but I kind of understand the
road that Tulle's going down here. The
big changes or I guess the yeah the
emissions are Jack Greish isn't
involved, Phil Foden is involved and
Jude Bellingham doesn't make it into
this squad as well. In terms of the
changes, Tukul's gone. I wanted to
invite everyone. Uh I watched his press
conference and and he was kind of big on
a few things that and kind of the the
team spirit that was apparently fostered
in that f in that last uh camp and he
wanted to kind of stick with that which
I think is really really interesting. So
Quanza is in which is maybe a bit of a
maybe a slight shock to some but he was
in the last one. Um Loft Chic replaced
Adam Walton. I'll come back to that. um
he replaced him in the last squad and
has retained his place. I think Walter
might got injured prior to that or or in
that moment. And Saka has come back in.
Madaweki's got injured. So sadly he's
kind of had to make his way out. And
Tino Livernto is not there. So a bit
lower on right backs, but you got Jed
Spence who can play right back or left
back. So he's not really got a problem
there. Kza, if you had to go and do it,
he could do that as well. So it'll be
interesting to see who he goes for in
the Wales game and the Latvia game
because the Latvia game thing to
remember with the Latvia game and this
is where it kind of leads onto the Dub
Bellingham situation is that with Jude
Bellingham
not being in this squad it is quite the
comment and I think it's deliberate um
and I think it's down to group dynamics
because and I think this could cause a
bit of a problem down the road but right
now I think it's a smart call. I think
Jude Bellingham is clearly a very very
high-profile person within the squad and
I love him. I absolutely love him and
you obviously want him in that squad as
well. But I think in terms of that group
valuing themselves and and really kind
of understanding like what they're about
like and and being important to the
team. I think Jude Bellingham does, you
know, if he wants to or not, I don't
think he means to do it. I think he does
take a lot of the spotlight, right?
So, I think to give this group their
moment on their own and to go and if
they beat Latvia get to the World Cup
themselves, that is a moment that this
group will have on its own and that will
bond them pretty tightly and I think it
will allow them to have um sort of
greater status individually amongst this
group without the sort of noise of of
Jude Bellingham. And by the way, this is
the JLA tactics board. So, there's so
many different great things you can do
to take your analysis to the next level.
A million different things here which I
can chuck on now, but I've got a whole
video on the channel that breaks it
down. And we've got a new addition, a
couple of new additions to it in terms
of how you can just like pick up the
whole squad. Oh, how you can pick up the
whole squad really easily and move them
about. You can switch sides now. It's
never been easier. So, if you want to
get involved, please do. Link is in the
description. Also, if you're a coach,
we've now got equipment that you can put
in as well. All sorts of different kind
of equipment and stuff like that. Um, so
definitely worth having a look at if you
are in the mood for it. So, um,
the thing with the group dynamics though
with Bellingham, so Bellingham, there's
two sides of it, right? There's this
group being left alone without Jude
Bellingham in it. And again, I'm not
saying Jude Bellingham's a problem, but
I'm saying he's a big big personality.
The other thing for me is
is is Jude Bellingham and how he will
feel. He won't be an outsider when he
comes back, but he will have kind of
missed something. So, his status will
have dropped just a little bit. And I I
don't think that's the worst thing. I
don't think that's the worst thing in
terms of humbling.
It's not I don't it's not about humbling
Jub Bellingham but like I think just
kind of taking down the temperature on
his um kind of importance in this group
because that could happen. You know, you
could get to the World Cup and he could
get an injury. Like this is England.
We've seen this several times. So I
don't I don't dislike that at all. Um
it's also never a great time to say that
we're going to do the squad selector on
Monday. So if you guys don't know, a lot
of you will because you're OG's. We've
always done a live stream where we've
gone through the squad I would pick
today if the World Cup was kind of, you
know, in the next week. It's always
really good fun. So, make sure you join
me on the James Ra channel for that. So,
Belling and the thing about TUL bringing
him out or or leaving him out or
dropping him or whatever it is, he's got
a valid reason. I think it helps with
the this group in terms of allowing them
to kind of stick their chest out to the
likes of Anderson to kind of really have
his place within this squad. Declan Rice
more and more. Although he's obviously
he's not new Declan Rice. Um Gordon
Rashford, a lot of them. I just think
Bellingham's such a big personality.
You're going to want him back. You know,
the squad is going to want him back. And
I think also the squad will accept him
back. But having these other guys
knowing knowing their role, but also
having an important role within the
these camps, I think it's really really
really important because I think
Jubelling is one of the few sort of
louder characters within it. And so
yeah, I just think it allows the status
of the rest of the group to to to fly
up. The problem this will cause down the
road is as I say, has Tool got the
minerals to leave out Palmer, Trent,
Foden,
and Bellingham and Wharton down the
road. I I don't think he has. I think
look, Foden has got much much better
recently. Can he keep that going? If you
can keep that going, you're going to
want to look to try and get him in.
Right. Wharton. Wharton is the one that
I'm really angry about if I'm honest. Um
I don't understand why Loft Cheek is
here. He will not be going to the World
Cup in my opinion. He's, you know, not
really starting for AC Milan. Generally,
Warton is, you know, a superb footballer
and
more of an obvious option to replace
someone like Anderson or to play in
front of Anderson as well. He's just an
exceptional player and I I don't think I
don't understand why Loftish Cheek is
there if I'm honest. So I think Walton
should have been in the squad unless
there's something that I haven't read
yet and if that's the case let me know
in the comments down below. But when
you've got the likes of Palmer and Trent
and Bellingham and Foden and maybe
Greish knocking about as well and Mowki,
who are you going to take out of this
group? And if you do take the, let's say
you take them out, right?
Is it gonna be Gibbs White? Is it gonna
be Morgan Rogers?
Is it going to be Bowen for Mowki?
Is it going to be Loft Chic? You know,
is it going to be Es like who like who
knows? But the point is that these
players are the key members of this
group right now. A group that is, you
know, doing doing pretty well.
So when you make those changes, are you
going to erode all of that team dynamic
um building that you've that you've
allowed yourself to build? That's the
thing that's going to hurt him. I think
just on the loft chic thing, like you
know, also someone like Curtis Jones,
why is Curtis Jones not ahead of Loft
Chic? I don't understand that. Tuk must
know something or not. I don't. Maybe
it's, you know, from his Chelsea days or
something like that. I don't really get
it. Um not bringing another right back.
back. I think someone like Tyreek
Mitchell is a little bit unfortunate
here. Yes, he's playing in a different
formation, but he's being allowed to
attack and then get back. That's the
similar thing that he would do here. So,
I think that's a little bit like I would
like seen Tyret Mitchell in here and
Spence as like one of these other
fullbacks and you bring Tyret Mitchell
here. I don't think you need five center
backs here, but it's not that big a
deal. You know, it's not worth kind of
getting too angry about. And then in
terms of the selection for the two
games, it's going to be interesting to
see what he goes for in the two of them.
I I expect the one thought I had was
that Bowen would start at some point. I
think Bowen will either start the Wales
game or the Latvia game. I think he'll
probably start the Wales game and be
given an opportunity. So, it's a huge
huge
um set of games for Jared Bowen because
I think you know he's captain, he's of
West Ham, he he's dealing with that kind
of pressure. This is a real real
opportunity for him to kind of jump the
queue in terms of Madaweki because you
might go Sack and Mowki. Are they a
little bit too similar? I think I don't
know. I mean, they're not that similar
to be honest, but Bowen does bring a
different kind of spark. So, I think he
needs a big big performance against
Wales or Latapia, depending on which one
he starts. And I think he will start one
of them for him to to sort of give
himself a real chance because there's a
really difficult decision on that right
hand side there. And then the same goes
for these guys in the middle. I think
that it's a really really tricky time
for Gibbs White as a loft cheek and
Rogers less so loft cheek. I just don't
see him being part of it personally. I'm
not trying to hammer him and maybe I'll
be wrong. That's and that's cool.
But for these guys with those other
names that we've spoken about, I would
expect at least two of those in
Bellingham and Palmer to be involved
obviously, right? So two of these guys
might not make the final squad for the
World Cup. So they someone needs to like
really really take the Bad Horns with
this one. Roger struggling for form for
for Aston Villa. Gibbs White, you know,
Forest aren't doing great either. So, I
think it's those two that are really in
the firing line. I think EZ will with
the sort of big club tax in terms of
Arsenal will help him in his desires to
be in that squad and obviously he's
going to be a key figure for Arsenal as
well and you'd expect him to do well.
So, Rogers and Gibbs White massive for
them as well. Anderson to continue on
what he's been doing. He's been
absolutely brilliant in that last set of
games. You want to see the same again.
Um and Declan Rice, I think, has been
superb as well. and it's going to be
interesting to see what kind of team he
sets up and if he continues down the
road. So, go check out the whole video I
did on the Serbia game. I do think there
is some elements he's taking from Bayern
Munich in terms of the way that he's
getting the best out of Kane. Let's just
go to it here because I think this was
the lineup and we spoke about it on that
that day that Kane he he was quite happy
to sort of drop deep once they lost the
ball and then Pigford could pick out
Harry Kane. Will they continue to do
that? That's something for you guys to
keep an eye out on. And obviously Malawi
not in this one. How will Jarro Bowen or
Sacka enjoy and thrive in that scenario?
Interesting stuff. Who missed out for
you? Um how are you feeling about it?
Make sure you join me for the squad
selector and uh I'll speak to you soon.
Subscribe while you're here. Cheers.