Imagine a game of baseball where a
pitcher doesn't allow any batter to even
reach first base once. This is what
baseball calls the perfect game. It's
incredibly difficult, but it's not
impossible. Since the beginning of Major
League Baseball in 1876, there have only
been 24 official perfect games. The
first was technically thrown by Lee
Richmond in 1880, but at that time,
pitchers could only bowl underarm and
the pitching distance was only 45 ft as
opposed to the 60 ft and 6 in today.
that was referred to in a newspaper as
quote the most wonderful game on record.
But the term perfect game didn't
actually come into use until Addy Joss
threw the fourth one in 1908. No player
has ever managed it twice, but Ron
Hassie was the catcher for Len Barker
and Dennis Martinez's games in 1981 and
91, respectively. Only one player has
managed a perfect game during the World
Series, and that was the New York
Yankees Don Lson in 1956. And the only
player to throw one since the
introduction of a pitch clock is Domingo
Hermon in 2023.