Right people, let's talk Arsenal versus
Newcastle. So much to unpack here. Uh
something that I spoke about on my JLA
Substack. Actually, I got asked what do
I feel like is going to be one of the
sort of big changes this season. I feel
like I'm seeing it more and more. And in
this game, I thought that we saw it as
well. I want to talk about Yarez. I want
to talk about his performance in this
game. I want to talk about the big
changes that occurred in this game that
led to the game kind of ending up like
this.
And I want to talk about the back two as
well. And actually the goals as well. I
think it was really really interesting.
Yes, they were all from set pieces, but
there was so much more to be discussed.
Let's start off with the two teams here
and then we can get into Yokarez's role
because actually I think the other thing
we've got to touch on is like the
psychology of this win and what it does
mean. it it's so much bigger than just a
normal lastm minute win. I really really
believe that on reflection. Right, let's
get into it and then I'll explain all of
that because these are the two teams and
as we know we were expecting, you know,
Newcastle to defend it the way that they
naturally do. You know, they're going to
have that mid block of that five, but
you've got the likes of Bruno, Tanali,
Joe Linton ready to snap in. They're
going to be physical. They were
physical. You know, that's absolutely
fine with me if I'm honest. I thought
the game was really, really physical. I
think does it go a little bit too far?
Maybe a little bit here and there. But
also, if everyone just got on with it,
then no one would be moaning and it
would have been pretty even. You
probably don't like that I've just said
that, but I did. Sorry. Um, if you like
honesty, subscribe to the channel
because I think that's that's a good
thing to like, isn't it? Isn't it? Is it
not? It's not. Is it not? Is it not? Is
it not? It's not. Is it not?
It's not, is it? But is it not? That's
not, is it? Okay, good to know. Um, so
here we go. We got the two teams here.
And what I thought was really, really
interesting was how Arsenal were able to
break on the JLA subsack,
which we've got link in description. You
want to get involved, we've got some
really great articles in there, and
we're going to be doing having really
kind of quite niche chats with tactical
people, which is super exciting for me
to kind of learn more all the time. But
one question I got asked on our COP
unfiltered
uh video that I did the other yesterday
the other day was what's going to be the
next change in football. I think the
next change is two strikers up top. And
the reason I think that is I think
having that second striker, shadow
striker, whatever you want to call it, I
think is becoming more and more
important as teams look to transition.
Thomas Frank spoke about it a year ago.
He's been doing it for a long time, but
you're seeing it up and down the league
and you're seeing it more and more. And
in an away game like this, the use of
Yarez having EZ with him was absolutely
huge in this game, I thought, and it led
to them having a lot more access into
central areas, but also you had someone
who could get you up the pitch because
in transition, it was one where it did a
lot of good for Arsenal and I thought
Joz in particular really really sort of
stood out for me. So this is Arsenal
kind of when they uh you know were
defending and Newcastle kind of going
for it a little bit here and the ability
for Yarez to be able to make that run be
that backboard but both drive in behind
into the channels or also be a target
man. I thought that is it's so basic and
traditional but it's so useful but it is
pointless if he is all on his own. But
having Ez as that sort of central
attacking midfielder or second striker,
let's say, and he was told to sort of
get up there and help him and be in and
around him, it led to so many great
moments. Let me show you exactly what I
mean, because
this is let's go through it because
there's loads here and I think there's
good bits and there's bad bits and
that's what I want to get into it with
Yarez's performance here because him
being that target man, this is a break
that I think Tim has been able to play
the ball to him. He's that backboard. He
takes center backs out out of position.
But if you don't have someone in this
area here, it's all a little bit
redundant because you're not really
hurting the opposition. But in this
moment here, you see one little pass and
it makes a huge difference in terms of
attacking the game and hurting the
opposition because as you can see here,
so this is him getting on the ball,
laying it off. Then you got someone as
brilliant as Sack is able to drive and
get into those central areas. And the
crucial thing here is having that second
striker. Now EZ is not going to, you
know, be a target man, right? That's not
what he's about. But the important thing
is, you know, the center back is now
kind of redundant because he's being
pinned. So now you've actually got
one, two, three, four against in truth
one, two. So it was really, really
useful having Yarez in those
transitional moments to help you move up
the pitch. Can Havitz do this? Yeah,
Havtz can do this. Absolutely. And I
think there is going to be that debate.
And so that leads to a fantastic moment
where they're able to get through the
center of teams quickly. We know how
they can have control possession and
they did often in this game. But I think
on another day maybe against a different
team that doesn't defend as well as this
or if it kind of fools your way, you're
in a much better position. And there
were moments throughout the game. This
is a moment where Yres can maybe go to
EZ maybe can he open up his body and
turn and go to Trussard who's on his way
as well. But understandably, Saka is the
aside here, so he doesn't want to do it.
But it's not the end of the world. Him
being that backboard allows him to play
the ball quickly. And I think he's
getting to grips with the physicality
here. And again, having a player that
can spin and drive with the intensity
that he's able to. One thing I would
say, can he show a little bit more
nuance at times? Can he bend that run
and be the other side of the center back
here? I think that could have I mean I
guess the one that thing that's good
about being this side is that you're
kind of keeping that center back honest
so he doesn't cut across. So maybe it's
a smart move but if he does go across
then maybe he can get the ball himself
and he's in because by the end of it
Saka now has to go down that side and
he's not able to pull the ball back.
Would there have been a bit different
way of doing that where you're able to
get into that area of the pitch. These
are the little things that Yokarez cuz
there are moments. It's not perfect, but
it is getting better. There are shoots
of hope here for Yarez. Yes, he's a
little bit clunky,
a bit cumbersome, but I think that's
what's going to come with him. But
there's going to be moments where you
absolutely love every second of it. Now,
the goals are interesting because I
think there's a set piece setup that
we're going to see more and more. And
what it is is this. So you saw it for
both first goals for both teams. This is
the corner. Plays it off here. And the
important thing is is getting into this
area here because from here you can put
a cross in
and you can go towards that back post.
Tell another one. Just go straight to
that back post. And by hitting that back
post, if everyone misses the ball,
that's fine. But what could be even
better to optimize it is can you get all
your big boys in a row here? And that's
exactly what they did so fantastically
for the goal Newcastle, but it's
something that Arsenal ended up doing
themselves as well. So here you go. You
can see the cross coming in here. Okay,
maybe it's not perfectly in that back
line, but one where David Rya maybe
can't come and get it, which is
important here, but as you can see, big
man, big man, big man, big man. Four big
mans in a lovely diagonal line, and it
means that they can go and get on the
ball that and it's in line with the
flight of that cross. I thought that was
a really really clever setup and
Voltomard himself spoke about how that
had been set up in training. This is the
other side of Jockarez I want to touch
on because this is one where there's a
lack of kind of nuance to his dribbling.
I think at times at no point during this
passage of play and I think a lot of
people might analyze this does he make
you think he's going this way at all or
truly slow you down to burst away? I
mean, has he got that outrageous burst
that he can get away from these big
center center backs because he's a sort
of big center back himself in terms of
his profile or has he got that
blistering pace just to go? The problem
he has here is I think he gets caught up
a little bit where he kind of goes away
right and so the center back's
completely in control then he trying to
cut tries to cut back for a second then
burst away but all the while I think we
know that he's kind of staying on at
that right side he goes he's trying but
it's not totally fluent and he kind of
takes away all of his passing options by
going down to that side and it makes it
easier for the goalkeeper as well to
sort of cut down the angle if he was
even able to get that yard in the and he
tries to chop back um onto his left
foot, but Malik Chow by this point
absolutely knows what he's doing. Knows
he needs to come back cuz he's not going
to go around the side. And so that's the
kind of the other side of of Jockarez in
terms of him and his kind of what's the
word just the sort of granular subtle
aspects to him as a player. What I
really liked and again go back to that
tactics board. You can see exactly what
we're talking about now is
just a lot more central. This will be
nice a minute. Let's do a little
diamond. Lot more central kind of uh
occupancy, right? If you think of that
line of of Newcastle getting inside it
and you've got players like Declan Rice
who are happy to play that ball forward,
like Zubmeni are happy to play that
forward. This is going to work really,
really well for Arsenal and this is the
next iteration. I think it's going to be
really interesting. We'll get on to
Odgaard's role here cuz Odgaard's role
in this game could be kind of the future
of his role in this team. Arsenal fans
been gasping for this. Play it into that
central area. I mean on this occasion
it's Timber there, but it's interesting
that at different moments Saka was there
as well, right? So he plays in here,
pops it off, plays it in to Yokarez.
This is all nice stuff. Yes, it's a
little bit uh clunky at the moment, but
it's coming. He actually does well to
get his feet out and then the defender
does really well to get back to him. And
if he was able to play that pass, then
Ez would have gone here. He would have
played it to Saka and would have been in
business. Saka could have made this
little run here. But I think
understandably thinks Yok is going to
get the ball to Ezer. That will be the
thing for Yokas. Can he play quicker? I
think he can once he knows everything
that's going on. It's a really good um
it's really good tackle by the end of
it. This is what we're talking about
with Sacka. Far more central here.
Trussard far more central. We've still
got that kind of diamond there which is
really really nice. I think away from
home because I think we know that this
team can recycle, can do the horseshoe
blah blah blah, but we're bored of it
and teams have figured it out. So to
have them concerned about what's going
on in central areas is really important
here. bouncing off. Esa doesn't actually
do very well with it in in the end. But
again, it's good play and it's the
ability to move the ball quickly and
move the ball forward in transition as
opposed to slowly working up the pitch.
And so there's so many positives here I
think from Yokarez and I think on
another day it does work out for him
much better. But this team in terms of
central access is so much better. Here's
a great example of it. EZ able to take
players out of the game and Zubendy
wanting to play the ball forward. But
just as importantly, zone bloody 14.
Yummy, yummy, yummy. Doing things,
taking players out of the game in zone
14. This is a moment where the ball
makes its way across to EZ and he's able
to take someone out of the game because
that is just what he does. Exactly that.
Takes someone out of the game and now
all of a sudden you got so many players
in such a like would you want you would
you'd want all those players there,
wouldn't you? And your two center backs.
It's amazing. This is such a dominant
team in terms of how they own the game
because they trust in these two center
backs. Look at all that space in behind.
I don't think I've ever seen a team as
confident in their two center backs as
this Arsenal team is. And so there is an
element of risk going backwards, but it
doesn't feel like that because of those
two center backs. But EZ attacking the
game, attacking within zone 14,
affecting the game. Zubamey with that
beautiful pass that he's able to loop
over and you've got all these players in
one little area like on another day you
get yourself a goal from it. So there
there were good elements of play this
moment where Yarez had a little slip.
Can his touch be better there? I think
this is just going to be part and parcel
of it. But if you go before that moment
in time again some of the nice stuff,
nice straight forward pass, no messing
pass into him, one touch and they're on
their way. And that again is the whole
reason why you want these two close
together. One touch into a he's on the
way. And again on another day, this is a
superb bit of defending. Amazing block.
Check this out. This is how it ended up
and it was amazing.
But it ends up like that. And the goal
comes the first goal comes from a corner
that Declan Rice wins. But he starts
here.
It ends up with him up here and Odegaard
is essentially on his own and you've
just got these three
as your sort of base. Now, first of all,
I thought Odigard looked really, really
comfortable in this position. I thought
he looked great. You know, with
everything in front of him, I think he's
far more comfortable. And when you think
of this double pivot
of of sorts that you see with Zubame
Mendy and Rice,
Zubamedi is happy to sort of wiggle
forward if he needs to. Odigard to a
point, but I think he doesn't actually
come out. But Declan Rice is happy to go
as well because he's got that drive in
him.
And I thought this worked really, really
well. And again, it's kind of it's a
risky situation, but it led to players
in those central areas in behind that
line of of Newcastle. And I thought it
was really really impressive stuff. Um,
and it leads to the goal. No shame. And
this is the thing like he the risks that
he was taking on this occasion I thought
were really really smart but it was part
of the attitude as well. So first of all
three players central area behind that
Newcastle line you know risk in terms of
Odigard being there and the goal comes
from this
move on one more Declar Rice. This is
sort prior to it where Odgaard gets the
ball. You've got your two center backs
here as we was talking about and Declar
Rice on his bike
and the goal comes from that. And what
was really interesting about the goal
was that the same idea as the first goal
for Newcastle was in place. This desire
to get the ball in a new zone here which
we've seen sort of several times you
know over the years I think with Man
City have been big on it Brenford have
been big on it. getting into this area
of the pitch. I think we're going to see
this more and more make short corners.
People trying to work their way to this
area here where they can put that cross
in and get that diagonal line to give
yourself a chance. And that's what kind
of comes. Moreno of course scores the
header in the end into this back corner,
but you got Celiba on his way into that
area as well. Jockz is maybe like a
little a second later. Ez, you've got a
whole line of people there. It's really
really not I mean it's it's something
that we've seen for a while but you see
things kind of become outrageously
prominent. I could see this becoming
outrageously prominent. So better from
Jockarez. I like the shape in
transition. They're still controlling
possession like they have done before.
Odigard maybe in a new role. Declin Rice
playing outrageously well. The back two
being sensational in that second half.
Gabrielle being just outrageously elite.
It is all those elements are coming
together.
And that win at St. James's Park has
been I mean it's been lacking hasn't it?
You know if you think of the year where
you were supposed to get in the
Champions League or over the last few
years they've really really struggled at
St. James's Park. So to get that win in
the last minute by being on the front
foot and attacking but also with an
element of control I guess as well. I
thought it was absolutely enormous. And
I think you've got two teams here in
Liverpool and Arsenal that are both
sensational and will dominate a lot of
games and score a lot of late goals, but
this is going to go down to the wire and
there's going to be games where
Liverpool kind of can overpower their
opposition maybe with a bit of
individuality, but the wholehearted
chemistry of that team is still
building. I think you can see that for
Arsenal, there's an element of
chemistry. One question I would chuck
out to you guys, answer this for me. The
two fullbacks, how do you feel about
those two? That was one question I kind
of had to myself. Look, defensively,
sensational. The work rate of the two
absolutely sensational as well. But from
an attacking point of view, are they
going to get and does it even matter?
Are they going to get you enough goals
and assists?
I don't I don't want to have a go at
either of their performances because why
would you? Like, you know, that's silly.
And I really love Caluri and his
dynamism and Timber just I mean, he's a
machine.
and and fantastic on the ball, but he
does naturally want to come back. He
doesn't wholeheartedly want to sort of
drive and dribble with the ball like a
Friong would or like when you think of
those top teams, their ability to go and
win the game for you. That's the thing I
would say about this team. The team is
sensational. They're not going to
concede many goals, but are they going
to score enough goals? I don't think
that is wholeheartedly going to go away,
but I think in transition, you've got
something now here where these two can
break for you and you can really hurt an
opposition.
Sorry, I just pressed something there.
By the way, this tactics board is
available. Link is in the description if
you want to have a go. Um, so yeah, I
think it's exciting times. I think this
title race is going to go down to the
wire, but I think this was so much so
much bigger a victory than people
thought. Let me know your thoughts in
the comments below.