Right then people, welcome back to the
rip effect with me and this week's
guest, the wonderful Culture Cams, who's
killing it on YouTube. If you've not
seen one of his videos, just click on
one and then you will see lots of them
and they will all nourish you with
footballing goodness.
>> Yeah, good promo.
>> Perfect promo. Perfect.
>> Uh, thanks for coming in, mate. We've
done a lovely juicy podcast on Man
United and and now we're going to have a
look at the Premier League summer
signing so far. So, one thing just to
not be hypocrites from the first
podcast, this is uh we've got some
different tiers here. Now, the tiers for
this are huge, huge potential, will come
good,
>> not feeling it, why refund.
>> Okay, cool.
>> Probably a bit too many. I might get rid
of one of them. We'll figure it out.
>> But the thing to remember here is it is
early days, but we're going to have a
nuance discussion and that's why you
guys are here. So, thank you for joining
us in this room virtually
>> and uh we're going to get into it. So,
because there are a lot of new signings
and they are all finding their feet,
some are finding their feet quicker than
others, but I think what's great is and
I know you and Le are big on the eye
test. I think I'm becoming I'm getting
bigger and bigger on the eye test.
>> Yeah. Welcome. I know.
>> Welcome. I think I'm kind of like I was
had a good discussion with someone about
this actually last week about
>> the balance between the two
>> and because I think people that turn
away from stats um are kind of missing
the point a little bit. The point of
stats is to you should see something
then you should be able to go I reckon
this stat and you find the stat and you
go ah
>> not the other way around. I think a lot
of people do it the other way around.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Anyway, the stats. So, the
stats are going to be pretty limited
here because it's early data set, but
that's part of the fun in terms of what
where we feel like they're kind of
going.
>> Let's start off with uh and we'll run
through as many as we can. Martin Zuber
Mendy
>> 26 come through the door. Seven
appearances, two goals, no assist. Um,
here's a ripple effect for you of uh
ripple effect of this season has seen
less need for Miles Lewis Skelly for
buildup purposes because you got Zubie
in there making Califury more important
and ahead of him in the pecking order.
Yeah.
>> So, let's let's touch on Zubi first.
Comes through the door.
>> He's a bit of me as a player. I'll be
honest.
>> Yeah. to your point on the previous
podcast, that first game against Man
United, I I think that hit him like a
train.
>> Yeah, it did.
>> He was like,
>> "What is this?" Like, "Why does the ball
keep going over my head?"
>> Yeah.
>> Um like a real different planet for him.
But I I feel like he's I think he will
be huge for them.
>> Huge.
>> I do.
>> I think
Let's get rid of huge potential. Let's
get that. Let's just do You're going to
do huge.
>> Okay. or will come good. So, I think it
will be huge for them. I think the way
Arteta is setting up with having Declan
Rice kind of with him a little bit at
times, it means that like different
people can like bomb on a little bit.
That's the one thing I've been a bit
quite impressed with him is that I
thought he I think we just sit there.
>> Yeah, I thought that too. But he's
actually going even in buildup. Declan
Rice is sometimes starting the buildup
and I I thought it was always going to
be um Zuba Meny picking up the ball from
the back four. So sometimes I see him
when they in possession, he's actually
higher up than Declan Rice, which is
quite quite interesting. It's not a
development that I thought was going to
happen.
>> I'm getting involved. You're not sure.
>> Yeah, I'm not too sure with Zubeni, you
know, like I'm not a fan of of um flimsy
defensive midfielders. Not really my
thing, you know what I mean? Unless
you're like special special. But
>> so with him, I'm your defensive
midfielder.
>> Yeah.
>> So are you are you an enforcer? me I get
about you know what I mean I'm quite
lazy though I'll be honest right I'm
quite lazy but I've got physical
strength you know I mean I got power
that's the thing I got power about me so
>> with me I'm not really a big fan of it
and I think
>> if you are going to be that
>> see I don't have power I think that's
the difference so smart he's so clever
he reads
>> the thing is like I look at him and I do
think yeah he reads the game and stuff
but I think if you are going to be like
a a flimsier type let me say what I say
is I see him
at a similar level to what Georgino
achieved.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> Interesting.
>> And that what is that? That's good.
Georgino was a good player, but
>> is it wasn't amazing.
>> Yeah.
>> That's how I kind of see Zub Mendy for
me.
>> I get what you're saying.
>> Like,
>> but even even Georgino I thought had a
it's early. It's very early by the way,
but Georgino had this kind of give me
the ball
>> about him. Zu Mendi. It could be by um
instruction, but it's not that right
now. But I think he will come good. I'm
not going to say poor signing or
anything like that, but I wouldn't say
huge.
>> Okay.
>> I still think Declan Rice's importance
is going to be far greater.
>> I just think, and again, this is
probably leaning on me in terms of like
the player that you wish you were.
>> Mhm. I love players that can see a pass
that no one else can see and then they
do that one and you go, "Oh,
>> yeah." Yeah.
>> Um and I think
>> like Declan Rice was getting I thought
Dean Rice was unbelievable in the last
game. Yeah.
>> And he's often unbelievable. So I kind
of like let it go. I don't really
understand any kind of critique of him
really cuz I just think he's brilliant
because Skoles had a go at him the other
day saying he's like he could be so much
better but he just does unnecessary
things. I'm like I mean I'm not gonna
argue with Skoles but I kind of
>> Yeah. I didn't I thought that was a bit
funny cuz the way he like the way he
gets about the pitch incredible man.
>> He's so complete.
>> It's like a modern
keen in a way.
>> Yeah.
>> You know what I mean?
>> But he played like he played a a pass.
He played a pass into EZ. Um and people
got a bit cra I thought they were going
a bit mad about the pass cuz it was
quite a simple pass. Um, but I think
Zubendi does that all the time and I
don't think people that will become like
a regular like yeah we know that about
him. So he might get kind of like
forgotten a little bit. I think he plays
the ball forward a bit more than Geor
personally.
>> You think so?
>> I think Georgie is a bit like
>> he was more metronomic give me the ball
and go yeah I get what you're saying. I
get I can hear that.
>> That's okay. We can disagree.
>> Yeah. I will come good.
>> Will come good. Okay.
>> Yes.
>> Well remembered. Uh sticking with
Arsenal. We'll work through them. Uh
Joarez.
>> Yarez.
>> How are you feeling about him? Not
feeling it.
>> You're not feeling it?
>> I'm not feeling it. I'll be honest with
you. I'm not feeling it.
>> I get that.
>> I'm not feeling it with Yarez. I I Your
for me, I I looked at him in in Portugal
and
I was genuinely looking at him and I was
like, what is his outstanding thing that
I think if he comes to the Premier
League, it's just going to easily
translate. And I didn't see it. And a
lot of people saying, "Well, Harland
played in this league." But and I'm
like, Harland is genuinely a physical
freak. Like his spee's like a physical
specimen. Like his genetic athleticism
is unreal. So that will translate. And
honestly, people may laugh because he
became kind of a meme or whatever, but
Darwin Nunez, I looked at him in
Portugal and I said, "Oh, what you have
can translate to the Premier League." I
would have never anticipated how bad he
was at at finishing. But that speed,
that athleticism, it still actually got
him pretty far at Liverpool. He just
couldn't finish it. Like he was a chance
magnet. And I thought to myself, but
Yarez, yeah, I know he's running past
these players, but he doesn't strike me
as the as the pestest athlete. He
doesn't strike me as the fastest guy.
And I was like, okay, how's it going to
translate? And I'm looking at him at
Arsenal. And I think any base level
striker for Arsenal should score about
15 goals. I think that Kai Havitz did
it. Jesus would have did it if he stayed
fit. Base level will be about 15 goals.
But do I look at him and think to
myself, I think he'll get that.
>> But do I look at him and I think to
myself,
>> oh, you're going to be Arsenal striker
for the next three years and they're
going to be relying on you to be scoring
20 plus and putting up crazy numbers.
No. And now look at he was he was he
just won the um J Müller award. He'll
never get that Arsenal. He'll never ever
get the the that level at Arsenal.
>> I don't think he's a great player, but I
think he will score goals. I look at his
touch sometimes. I look at
>> the way he occupies center halfs and I'm
like
not really my type of player. I'll be
honest.
>> He needs to get cuter. He really does
need to get cuter because I think he
what is interesting I would put him in
>> I get why you're not feeling it. I would
put it in will come good. Okay.
>> But but how good? Like I would say like
I think you'll get 15 easy, right? I
think so too
>> because I think currently he's like this
battering ram, right? And different
center backs are are like kind of walls
>> and with the right one you could just
you can get push through it.
>> Yeah.
>> When you see him against,
>> you know, the lit and
>> some of these different guys, yeah, they
seem to be able to like deal with them
pretty easily, right?
>> Because there's no subtlety to it, you
know? It's like you fight fire with fire
and you should be you should be all
right.
>> I think against the other teams
>> where you don't need that same kind of
subtlety,
>> I think you'll score a lot of goals. And
that's what I said a couple of weeks
ago. So far, I guess it's true. It feels
like and I thought he had a little bit a
few unfortunate moments against
Newcastle, but there's one moment where
he gets kind of put through and he has
to run against Malik Chow and as he's
driving, he doesn't do anything
outrageously wrong, but you you know,
it's so comfortable.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> It's so comfortable. And so he needs to
progress and he needs to develop even at
kind of this age. And I think that was a
debate with him and Sesho was that you
felt like Sesko's got more like room to
progress
>> and maybe more like
>> natural raw bits to him whereas Joarez
is going to be that battering now in
terms of getting you where you want to
be which is to win the league.
>> I think a lot of points that they
dropped last year was
>> was down to not conceding goals, it was
down to scoring goals. So I think in
those other games
>> Yeah. But the thing is is it going to be
like that though? Is it necessarily
like, you know, is the game so black and
white that it's like, oh, last season we
didn't beat the little teams, but we
were good against the big teams. So, at
Yakarez, he's just going to score
against all the little teams and then
we're going to do the same thing we did
against all the big teams, and that
means we win the title. That seems a bit
too
>> Well, I think first of all, you got like
Havitz. Havitz is not just going to stop
playing. So, like you could bring him in
certain games. I also think we've kind
of seen it when people talk about the
handbrake and stuff like that.
I think I I think Arteta thinks that the
league will be won and lost on how you
get on against the other guys as much as
>> the games against Man City and
Liverpool. Those games are huge. Of
course they are. And if you can get the
win, great. If you don't lose, that's
that's pretty cool, too.
>> That was Fergie's mantra. Fergie
honestly did not care about the big
games the way we used to win leagues and
not beat the big teams a lot of times.
>> You'd beat everyone else.
>> Everyone else would beat. And maybe that
is what our test was thinking. Like
Bergie used to be like, "Yeah, go
especially away from home. just don't
lose. We don't lose away from home. He's
he's happy man cuz it's only
>> three four fixtures. Well, obviously
that stacks up, but
>> also I don't I don't think I always
think it's so more so than ever. I think
it's harder to win those other games
like those Bulma like uh like you you
know we were talking last one you got
Sunderland teams are quick. They got
physicality. They're good in transition.
They're organized. Teams have never been
more organized than this. Teams have
never been bigger than this. So then
you're making it a bit of a set piece
game. So that's a bit one thing for sure
is that Arsenal I still think even with
even if Yarez I don't think he's going
to flop but even if he did flop I think
Arsenal can still win the league in
spite of that. I do think they can you
know what I mean like he's got to be so
bad for him to have a real effect on
what I think Arsenal can do this season.
Yeah, I do. I feel that like that Lukaku
just like can't seem to score against
that I think that could be a tag for him
unless he can get a lot cuter a lot
quicker. Um but still he still
facilitates the team in different ways.
It just like eye test wise it doesn't
look great.
>> Uh you'd love him you'd love him in
midfield.
>> Ez I've spoken too much about EZ.
>> Yeah. Huge.
>> So So you tell me about do you you think
huge? huge if he's allowed to play in
the 10 on the left hand side. I've seen
as a for England on the left hand side.
We saw a little bit of it for Arsenal.
It's not his best role, man. It's not
his best role. You don't want like
you're trying to turn him into like a
one v one kind of player and as a
central dribbling like running in the
middle of the park. He's he's top three
in the league in my opinion. If you're
talking about getting the ball and
running through players in the middle of
the pitch, I look at as a Kuna's really
good at it as well. But you running
through people so underrated. That skill
as well is so difficult.
>> So underrated. And I think if he if they
can get him in that role, you know what
I mean? Like he moves the ball quicker
than Odegaard. He's more direct than
Odigard. He he runs past players better
than Odigard as well. Not this not to
disrespect Odard in any way, but I think
he excites people as well. You're
talking about low blocks, mid blocks.
When you play against low blocks and you
play against mid blocks,
>> you need someone that can carry the
ball.
>> Penetration is important, right? You
need someone that can commit you. If I
know Ez's on the ball,
>> you're going to have to go to him.
You're going to have to go towards him
and then he'll go past you and then all
of a sudden he's gone past you. Oh, Jo
has slipped that run. That's a goal for
him. But if you're got an ode who's not
going to do any of that, he's going to
pass it around. He said, that's how
teams just set themselves up. And I
think Arsenal kind of have a
>> little bit of a cheat code there with
him in the 10 in terms of playing
against these mid blocks and these low
blocks. So
>> I think it's a huge sign if he plays in
the 10 role. The left I'm just I'm
really hoping for his sake they don't
put him on the left hand side. Honestly
because Artet is not the type of manager
that's like play on the left but then oh
you're on the left but it's a free roll
off the left. It's not. It's you're on
the left. You know what I mean? So so I
want him to play in the 10 role.
>> I couldn't agree more. Yeah, I think I
said it with Le a couple of weeks ago
was like I could see him in that I liked
him on that right that is he's not right
sided 10 but he's actually what you saw
against Newcastle we actually he that
sort of second shadow striker so to the
point of Odigard with the famous mid
block when you haven't got the ball
where he becomes part of the two
>> as they can do that
>> and and he just he beats players because
me and Kai we've spotted it once and now
we can't we can't unsee it we're doing
we're gonna work on a video about it he
beats players is without touching the
ball. See
>> how mad that is?
>> Well, he's like not he's not like he's
not moving it moving it moving. It it's
>> that just glides in it.
>> It just glides past. It's so special.
>> And and he's a he's an massive you what
one of the things that Arsenal they were
genuinely probably top bottom three in
the league last season in terms of
transitions. And now a lot of people are
going to say, "Oh, we still scored
transition goals." I mean transition
goals will still count. booting the ball
long to sack
>> and then he brought the ball down
against Liverpool and then scored.
That's individual brilliance. But in
terms of like, you know, those counters
at their best, you remember when like
KDB will bring the ball forward,
Sterling's running off, Sane's run, you
know what I'm talking about,
transitions. Arsenal were really bad at
that in terms of turning defense into
attack quickly. I think EZ also helps
that. He's one of the best ball carriers
in the Premier League. Get him the ball
on a on a transition, everyone can just
go. Whereas again, touches, small
touches, he's not the power to keep
going and run and bring them forward.
So, I think with EZ in there,
>> it's it's massively going to help them
in that 10 roll, man. Honestly,
>> I agree. Huge been pretty consistent
with this one. I know like it's it's a
weird one for me with cuz it's like it's
the first time people going, "Well,
you're biased."
>> Yeah.
>> And I don't really get that much, but
I'm like I am, but I can still see and
you just for a reason. You said it for
me.
uh Keller to move over to a couple of
Brenford boys.
>> Keller I mean that's a good signing.
>> He's done well man. I think that's I
mean obviously pretty pricey to go
there. Um Fleckham was um pretty uh he
actually made money off Fleckenham go to
and Fleckenham was his uh he was really
he highly rated by Brenford. No one else
really spoke about it cuz up there with
like
>> all the save charts in Flecken was
always up there isn't it?
>> Yeah. And I always there's a my mate was
on and there's a forum called the
Griffin Park grapevine and they'll have
like who their man of the match is and
Flecken would like win it regular or be
right up there.
>> He was good. I think Kell is a really
good replacement.
>> Amazing replacement. I'd love to know
the contract and what the situation is
there. 26
>> come in obviously making saves from
penalties had a couple of like shaky
starts at the beginning of it but I
think that can't go wrong.
>> Yeah. Like even and I know this bit
disastrous if but the initial thinking
going into the season is obviously not
that you know you go down but if
something like that was to happen
that's a really good sellable asset.
>> Yeah he'll he'll move on he'll be back
in the Premier League.
>> Yeah I don't think I mean feels like
Brenford Brenford
>> you know better than I thought to be
fair.
>> They are I think they're going to be a
hard watch.
>> Yeah Keith Andrews he has you can see he
is a set piece coach in it. You can see
it. I mean, what's all these long
throws, bro?
>> It's everywhere. What?
>> Here's the stat. So, I I said this week,
we we make a short for the Premier
League.
>> Okay.
>> And I was like, we need to do a short on
long throws. And uh we found a stat on
it. Um and it was like
>> prior to this season, long in terms of
per game, how many long throws they
were,
>> it's generally like one point something.
>> It's now like nearly four.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. Everyone's at it.
>> What do you think the reason for that is
though? cuz I actually always thought
set pieces are very underutilized in
football. I always I've always thought
that you know
>> do you know what the biggest thing is?
>> Yeah.
>> You can't be offside.
>> There we go. Launch that.
>> So if you think you know if you think of
a game of football the the pitch is as
big as the defenders decide to a point,
right? Because if they go they're
offside. Leave them
>> with a throw on. If they go you have to
go with them.
>> Yeah. So all of a sudden the ball is and
when you're throwing the ball you should
>> be pretty accurate with it, right? So
you're guaranteed the ball
>> going into the danger area
>> with loads of players there.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think the throwins, look,
Tony P is probably sitting here
listening to this and thinking, "Oh,
well guys, I told you 10 like 20 years
ago." But but you know what it is,
right? I think yes, you should see
corners, throwins, free kicks. They are
the opportunity for you to do something
unopposed.
>> They should always be maximized. Always.
When I saw people criticizing set piece
again about Arsenal, I'm like, finally
there's a team that actually putting
priority to a free opportunity. Like it
doesn't make Yes. launch that long throw
into the box. It should be seen
>> as in a way another corner.
>> It it really should be like you
shouldn't want the ball to go out the
pitch. Soon we're going to see players
like like like you remember that famous
clip where against Stoke where the guy
kicked it out in for a corner instead of
a throwing.
>> Yeah.
>> We're probably going to get a lot more
of that soon. Like there's going to be
teams that like this team actually the
data tells us they're better from
throwings than corners kick the ball off
for a corner. Hey, I I remember QB
played Milwall and we had this uh they
had this guy this long throw
>> and it was like it's exhausting to watch
though
>> but when it's you it's just like
>> it's anywhere in that half
>> it's like he does this whoop and but
fortunately I mean we drew the game one
all but he got sent off
>> this guy we're like thank god for that
we got to deal with this like because
like you say with I think with thrones
in particular it's so unopposed And the
angle, it's not like you've got to whip
it on to it.
>> It's a straight.
>> It's straight. Yeah. Cuz if you if you
think this is the other thing I think
you'll see more and more and more, which
it has got more prominent, but I think
maybe with corners as well. You think of
the goal Arsenal's goal, Newcastle's
first goal, and the goal against
Everton, which came not from the initial
corner, but when it came back out, that
cross
>> on the corner of the penalty box. And
that more so than ever before like
you're having four, five, six foot two
plus guys in a diagonal line in line
with that back post. It all feels pretty
obvious but teams are really really
working towards that
>> and you saw like Volto um obviously say
Artic looks like Maria.
>> Um and yeah the goal was it Keem with a
good header as well. You're going to see
that more and more and more. Yeah. You
don't want it to be everything.
>> No you don't. You don't like you still I
don't want to see it from like I want to
see it from when it's like around the
boxish area. So let's say like the
corner to maybe like the 18 yd line or
something. Great. I don't want to see
teams just getting just over the halfway
line and just now all the defenders
going you now start launching it. That's
when the game's gone. That is when the
game's gone.
>> Uh Jordan Henderson 35year-old six
appearances.
>> You know I laughed at this signing.
>> Did you? I did laugh at it
>> about this because you know you with the
boys you're like
>> you know you're not backwards and coming
forwards you know you say go this is
this
>> and you have to eat a bit humble pie
which I like I think it's good that you
got that in you.
>> Yeah I mean cuz he schooled us he
actually schooled us like you know I was
doing a watch along for the game.
>> Yeah
>> and I was like
>> where is that available?
>> That's on my YouTube channel. That's on
my YouTube channel. So I was watching
the game. I was doing a watch along and
I was like I was like oh literally it's
like commentators curse. I was like,
"Come on, man. We got a game. We got We
got Jordan Henderson midfield."
Literally just clips it over the top
just as I said it. Bam. Thiago goal. So,
you know what? Credit to him cuz I
actually thought it's going to be like a
walking disaster. Like Jordan Henderson
coming in 35 years old. Keith Andrews in
charge. Wow. Relegation is just looking
absolutely perfect for them. And he's
coming actually did decent. You know
what I mean? I haven't looked at him as
a glaring
>> unbelievable.
>> Yeah. Like you know what is it? I I have
got to give respect to Henderson as a
just a top top model pro
>> and those model pros can play on for
years and years and years just through
their leadership. Now I think the reason
why I'm so against Henderson is because
he keeps getting called up for England
and that is really irking me.
>> So maybe that was a bit of a effect of
it. But do you know what? I will give
Jordan Henson credit. I had him I think
I think I did something where it was
like worst sign of the season. I think I
had him as worst sign of the season. I
genuinely think I did. That's
>> so
>> I think it's smart and I think if you
think of the way that they're playing it
works as well and
>> age ain't nothing but a number.
>> Yes.
>> 35 he's still got he's still got legs
enough. Yak maybe takes a second longer
to get there if he's got a bit of
protection around him legs around him. I
think he's in an okay place. So uh
Keller
>> I think
I think I think both of those are like
you're not are you feeling Henderson?
Have you moved away from that?
>> I'm going to put Henderson as will come
good.
>> Okay. Is there something? Is there
something Is there something between
will come good and huge?
>> I had huge potential.
>> Maybe that doesn't work. We can always
change it.
>> Keller is huge.
>> Just give it you can say where you can
give it wherever you want.
>> Keller is huge because if Brenford are
going to stay up, he needs to have a big
season.
>> Yeah.
>> So Kell Keller is huge. Henderson I'm
going to say will come good.
>> Okay.
>> For the season after this, guys, he's on
his own. You know what I mean?
>> I think they're both huge if I'm honest.
I think Anderson I think like him as a
and it feels a bit lazy analysis but
actually people don't concentrate on it
enough is like the leadership is is
enormous and the communication like I I
speak about this all the time but I went
to England Senagle in Qatar I've never
ever heard someone bark like that not
literally like just going at Sacka like
constantly
>> and I think it's yeah and he does it in
a way so Van Djk I was watching Van Dijk
Dan D was hammer ing Kenate at the
weekend. Move it like move it fast.
>> Play the part. I couldn't believe and
Kenate had a tough time. I think a big
part of that was
>> Van Dijk kind of on him. Yeah. A little
bit as much as a few different things,
right?
>> But yeah, Van Djke I feel like he's a
bit more gently a bit more like Mooney
than Henderson.
>> Yeah. Henderson. I think in a team like
that where you might be going through
difficult patches, won't have the ball
as much, you've got to have that
organization to keep you going. And I
think he I think he'll be huge. I really
do.
>> Xiao Pedro,
>> it's an interesting one.
>> They're struggling a little bit.
>> It is an interesting one cuz Jao Pedro
has quietly gone from oh the hope nine
to actually he's not really a nine, is
he? That's what I'm starting to mean. So
when that starts to happen,
>> Maize is like he's a bit like he's the
same way. He's kind of like he's not
really a nine, but he's not getting
opportunities and stuff. And I'm like I
saw a stat apparently that he his only
shot on target was the goal against West
Ham in September,
>> right?
>> So I'm like, wow, that means he's not
really getting anything. And the type of
player he is is that Jao Pra is not
going to wait for chances. He's going to
drop deep and try and run past players.
And he's very Gabrielle Jesus about him.
So then that also then limits you from
getting chances because you're trying to
create your own chance all of a sudden.
So he's in a tough position because
already if you're only six games in and
people are like, "Oh, you're actually
not a number nine."
>> Then you got a concern there. People are
generally talking like maybe he'll get
20 goals this season. And I was like
that's
>> I mean I've not heard I I'm not out and
I'm not about like reading too much of
that but I'm surprised but I'm surprised
but that like two weeks ago he was like
signing of the season. This is what I
mean, right? And now you're looking at
it and I'm like, hm, were we just all
excited off the club world cup a little
bit?
>> Well, but I mean, we're suggesting that
that's true. I don't think that's true.
>> I get you in terms of like him going
looking for the ball a little bit too
much.
>> I I mean, I think
>> is he a nine though?
>> Is he a nine?
>> Cuz some people like, "Oh, no, play J."
But now you got Palmer, you got Enzo
Fernandez who's turned into like Kevin
Nolan regen and it's like
>> it's about what do you want? Like do you
>> So do you want Yarez Dap N? Is that what
is that what Chelsea want?
>> I think that's Chelsea heritage manel
situation is a complicated one
>> to Yeah. Oh yeah it is. I mean all the
ones that I've worked out Jimmy Floyd
Hasselbank and then Drogba and Costa and
like they felt like proper even Jaru to
an extent.
>> Yeah.
>> And then you got these ones that Chelsea
had Maratas and stuff and then J Pedro
and stuff they're just a bit
>> you need a firm Yeah. They need a firm
one.
>> Feels like a Chelsea striker but if he
had the quality to match of course that
that's up for debate for people
>> but the way he plays feels like a
Chelsea striker
>> but again it's a new Chelsea in It's not
the same Chelsea. So,
>> yeah. And I think there's there's been
things at play, right? If you think the
last two Premier League games, players
sent off in both. I think that system
struggles
>> once you're once you lose a player cuz
it's a kind of about utilizing the width
a lot of the time. That was what I was
going to say about Pedro is like when
you've got the wingers, wide players
that they have, they are wingers. Yeah.
They are not um I mean go a natural
movie is slightly different but they're
not like a I'm going to make that guy
going to run in behind you so you
dropping deep's okay like like a you
know like Salah and Gako so when he is
doing that instead of being like the the
point of the arrow let's say
>> like if you think of me at leard was
that like he'd stay up there right
>> so that could be a bit of a problem with
with Pedro at times but losing a couple
of players isn't isn't great that said
it's not a great start to the season you
know not being able to break down Palace
who But we know they're really really
good defensively. West Ham 51 win. Yeah.
But West Ham are pretty bad. I think
four of those goals are from corners.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Three, four set pieces.
>> Fulham, good home win at Derby.
Brenford, that's two derbies to be fair
to you. There's three. That's four.
>> They stayed in London. They stayed in
London up until Man United. And that's
why beginning of the season,
>> I put Chelsea to be after five games top
of the table cuz I feel they're not
traveling. They're just going to
>> blow blow these London teams away. And
it's not like
>> look at it that way.
>> Do you I do I was thinking about if it
was like Tottenham and Arsenal in there
where I know these are London derbies,
right? But Tottenham and Arsenal and
maybe West Ham are the ones that are
maybe a bit more something to them,
right?
>> This is Man United lens coming out,
right? This let me tell you where you're
wrong.
>> Like but do do Chelsea view like Palace
as like a rivalry?
>> That is irrelevant.
>> You think so?
>> Do you know what's relevant?
>> What do you think?
>> What do Palace think? What do Brenford
think? M
>> so when Brenford go and play
>> okay I get what you're saying
>> when Brenford go and play Man City
>> big game but you know probably not going
to win that one blah blah blah blah
>> when you playing when it's London games
and especially if you are the favorite
>> that game goes from likelihood of
winning being that to that
>> because this is a cup final for Palace
and for for
>> I didn't think of it from that angle to
be fair I was only thinking about it
from that is a good point very very
>> so those London games are really
annoying
more cuz even if you have like QPI Lynn
Championship where we'd have a lot of uh
you know when we there were a lot of
London they're all in the Premier League
now annually but like when they were all
there you'd go even like Watford or
Charlton you go
>> it's not really a derby but it kind of
is and you're up for it so like and I'm
not I don't know if Watford care or not
but it just adds an annoy Yeah. an
annoyance.
>> That's a good point. I was only thinking
about it in a way of like
>> ain't got to travel far.
>> Yeah. they're just gonna it's gonna be
kind of comfortable and stuff
>> and they're the better team. So I was
thinking all right that's good for them
to start that way but when like the away
games you know you don't want to go
Newcastle you don't want to go I was
thinking oh away games perfect
>> but to be honest I didn't think about it
from the lower teams point of view that
yeah they're going to get up for it.
>> Yeah cuz in truth you're actually better
off going further a field before the
Champions League kicks in
>> and you got like the churn and the
league cup and those things. Um, so
yeah, interesting. The um, so Pedro,
will he come good?
>> I'm going to say he will come good
because I can't see him being a flop.
>> Um, and I like the player. My thing with
Yarez was I don't like the player, but I
do think he would do okay.
>> So I had to put him not really feeling
cuz I'm not I'm not really feeling the
player.
>> But I do like the player of Pedro. So
I'll say we'll come good.
>> Okay. I I really rate Pedro.
>> I've got I think he will come good.
>> I think we're good.
>> Yeah. But him being that lone striker is
slightly slightly problematic because I
don't think he I don't think he
wholeheartedly wants to be he like him
with Wellbeck amount of goals where he
got the the G, but Wellbeck had like
>> they zipped into Wellbeck. He popped it
off beautifully and Pedro's facing this
way with Mint and um Mita ready to go.
But I think he will overall come good.
Maybe not huge though.
>> Garnacho and Gittens. We put them
together.
>> 92 minutes for Garnacho so far. 215 for
Gittens. Combined cost of around 90
million. Selling Noni Mawa. He's a
ripple coming.
>> And Nicholas Jackson has reset the trust
cycle for Enzo Maresa. Chelsea's model
relies on signing young players who are
then developed to fit their system and
grow into their surroundings. last
season. Two of Chelsea's main attacking
options, Noni Madaweki Jackson, both of
whom were in their second full season at
the club, had begun to earn Mesca's
trust. However, by selling these
players, Chelsea have now seemingly
reset the process, signing Gitens, who
is extremely talented, but also
extremely raw, and Garnacho, who has to
prove himself after his troubles at Man
United.
>> You agree with that?
>> Yes, I agree with it.
>> The settling period is important. I I
was thinking about this for like maybe a
future podcast of like
or if you're predicting a new season.
There's something smart in going who's
in their second season.
>> I think there's something about that
when they like you go, "All right, I've
lived here a year. I understand the
rhythm of all of this and now I can
maybe like push on whereas like for
these guys Esau as well of course it's a
lot of new stuff going on." And that's
awkward when I think Chelsea have come
off the summer that they've had.
>> Yeah. cuz everyone thinks like, oh,
you'll be the ones
>> and I'm we're not seeing it so far.
>> Feel like
not really feeling these. Not really
feeling these. And the reason is because
I don't think the expectation of what
Chelsea need is what those players will
give them. You know what I mean? Chelsea
though Giton's not really feeling that
one. And Ganacho, when I'm looking at
Ganacho, I know Chelsea because he got
decent GA and stuff at United. I do
think Chelsea fans are going to expect
that but even more in abundance because
Chelsea's attackers none of them
guarantee you goals at the moment. None.
J Pedro don't guarantee you goals. Even
when his highscoring seasons at Brighton
10, he scored 10 penalties in one
season.
>> Do you know what I mean? So, he doesn't
guarantee you goals. You look at the
right winger, Pedroto literally does not
give you goals.
>> And then you look at the left winger and
I think that left winger, if it's
Ganacho, eventually they're going to
expect a lot of end product from him.
And I've watched Ganacho, that end
product may come. However, you are going
to have to roll with the frustrations.
Oh my god, there's going to be so many
times it's not going to come. So, it's
kind of like
>> a tough one. Chelsea is not Man United
as well. He came through Carrington and
we often
give people time a lot of the time and
you know we we're we pride ourselves on
giving players time and all this stuff.
Chelsea, they're not that type of
football club especially because they're
bringing in so many revolving door. It's
going to oh yeah, you're here for a
stay. We'll sell you next summer 35.
We'll take a 5m minute loss if we need.
Actually, Chelsea are great sellers. So
they'll probably make profit somehow
>> and then that's all it is. So with
Gitens not really high on the player to
to be honest. Um
>> I don't see okay I know they're not
playing in the same role cuz non is
obviously on the right hand side but I
look at like Git I don't see him as an
improvement on like a nonies and stuff.
So when I'm looking at Ganacho and
Gitens, I am not really feeling combined
90 million when you think to yourself,
what if that money could have just been
used on a
>> I don't know 90 million on a on a rafale
or something like that or you know a
real needle mover. I don't see these two
moving the I do not look at them two and
think
>> I don't even look at them and think
Chelsea's improved as attack um attack
has improved from last season.
>> Yeah, I don't. I think has it
>> caught in the It feels a bit caught in
the churn
>> of it like now
>> like I don't know enough about Giddens
to be honest like I've seen bits and
I've seen a couple of games with him
playing in and and you know there's lots
there's lots to likes I wouldn't you
know and again with all of these guys
everyone's ready to prove us wrong
that's the whole point but it's just
having a discussion but the
>> but yeah I agree with you like
>> it's funny isn't it like when Nimiki
went
>> you know the feeling around that and
then a couple of games you go oh Yeah,
>> he's I like him. He's direct. He's
>> I had high expectations for Chelsea this
season. They they really they really
disappointed me and
>> I do think I got caught a little bit
with the the Club World Cup and the way
they ended the season. I was thinking,
"Oh, okay. Chelsea might be one of them
ones." But now I'm looking at it and I'm
like I just had the lens over my eyes
because honestly I'm looking I'm like
there's not much they got going like
they really need they need a special
Cole Palmer season again and I don't see
that coming because you can't really
he's actually quietly having fitness
issues like Cole Palmer these days. So I
can't see them
>> I need more anger in that team. Like I
feel like there
>> they feel a little bit like there
>> I'm fed up. It feels like it not sulky
but like
>> and not I don't want to say soft but
like it's just young where you go go
>> like Henderson that when you think you
hard like like sort of like standard.
Yes. That's what I was going to say.
There's a few like plays well.
>> Yeah.
>> I think Kaisedo I think they're the I
think week in week out those are the
only two consistent players. Kaisedo and
Kukara and that's a concern. That's only
two of 11. So,
>> and the like the system
Yeah. I'm not sure the system will ever
get an outrageous amount over out of
those wide players in terms of like what
you really really really are after. Um,
so yeah, yeah, not feeling it.
>> Not feeling at the moment now.
>> And I don't think you'll get a full
refund.
>> That's the thing because if it's 90, you
know, what's that 45 maybe, you know,
Gens was more, wasn't it? I think it
>> was 55. I think it was, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Are you going to get full
refund?
>> I don't know. I'm not sure refund can be
put in there.
>> Um, right. Let's move on. Jack Greish.
>> So,
>> yeah.
>> Huge.
>> I think so.
>> Do you know what the problem?
>> The problem not that he's got or or
sorry, the hidden weapon that he has is
the amount of and it's it hurts him too
a little bit. He gets fouled so much.
>> I've never seen anyone get fouled so
much.
>> He's also brilliant at winning a foul.
>> Um, which is great. That's why I'd
always kind of if I can get him in an
England squad, that could be really
useful because if you've got 20 minutes
left, go, "Look, mate,
>> let's get Harry on. Let's get Harry
McGuire on. Let's score some goals." But
the um the one question I would have,
right,
>> a question for all Everton fans, all
fans, full stop.
>> Um he's got 34 progressive carries so
far this season. And I actually when we
did a video on the Premier League a
couple of weeks ago about him and it was
amazing like at this point in the season
the reps he's getting in terms of let's
get the ball to Jack Greish and Jack off
you go.
>> Mhm.
>> He's going to have so many hopefully
opportunities to really you know create
good moments but also then if that's not
really working go win some fouls. Set
pieces come from that as well.
>> But um I don't know if this is the
option but it sounds like it is. Would
you pay 50 million if you're Everton for
a 31-year-old Jack Greish at the end of
this season?
>> No.
>> Regardless of how well he plays,
>> I wouldn't do that. No. Because you just
don't know when that star can come. And
when you look at Everton, you said huge.
>> No, I think it's huge, but they need to
negotiate that down.
>> Give me a 30 million. 30 million. Can
you do that? But 50 million
especially Everton as especially as a
football club. Everton, they are like
the lower table Man United in terms of
their business over the last 10 years
has been scandalous. Do you know what I
mean? In terms of how much they spent
and what they've actually got out of
them players. So, Everton really got to
think about that like 50 million for a
31 year old. And right now, Jack Greish,
the concern is we always talk about
players contract year players, right?
Like players that are playing for their
contract. Jack Grees right now is
playing for a move. Whether it's for
Everton or it's for someone else, he's
playing and a World Cup year. He's got
there's so much motivation. Chip on his
shoulder cuz he got moved out of city.
He needs to get a contract forever from
Everton or someone else. And that's
three motivations.
>> He's getting so much love, isn't he?
>> And he's instantly walked in getting the
love becoming a bit of a cult hero.
>> But you now signing 50 million all of a
sudden it's World Cup years done. I can
settle and you might not get the same.
>> I think he's got two is it two is it two
years
>> really? I wonder if he did he sign he
wouldn't have signed any kind of
extension I'm guessing.
>> Um if I can even find it here contract
expires 2027.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. What's that? Two years
>> and then by the time it's done we about
one year. 50 is a lot. It's a lot. It's
a lot of money.
>> I think you get I think 30 might I think
30 is good.
>> Yeah. I think that's
>> if any could be quite pushy with it cuz
if he's just like utterly loved and goes
look I just want to spend next five
years here.
>> Yeah.
>> Then like there's that could work in
terms of getting that price down. But
yeah, interesting. Uh yeah, I think huge
this season for them. I think they'd be
fine regardless, but it could be the
difference between 12th and eighth or
ninth
>> if you if they really really go for it.
Although you've not been outrageously
good so far,
>> but yeah, it's great to see him there.
Good to see him getting on the ball,
getting reps. Yeah,
>> Jbury Hall
>> there as well. He's only 27. Jbury Hall.
Yeah,
>> he might be the first person to get
suspended for bookings this year. And
one of those ones was from the quick
>> free kick.
>> Um, this is I think this is
>> I think this is Oh,
>> I like about Will come good. I think
it's huge. I think it's huge cuz I think
he'll be that's it now.
>> Yeah,
>> I think he stays there. I think he's at
least there. I think he's there five
years.
>> I see that.
>> And I think they love him and I think
he's great.
>> I like that signing.
>> Yeah,
>> I like it. I I'll put it as huge as
well.
>> There are players like that though. If
they're at a bit like we were talking
last podcast, we were saying certain
players if you brought them back into
Man United would people just turn their
nose up at him.
>> Yeah.
>> J Hall, I think if he if he goes that is
his
>> that's his level. That's his saying that
is that is I mean that's there's no
shame in that man. You know what I mean?
There's no shame in some people
>> good player
>> finding their level and some people are
just steady not steady but some people
are just performing Premier League
players for their career. Like it's I
was talking to Aobi about it um when I
interviewed him and we were like I was
like it's actually incredible that
you've been a Prem player your whole
career like but you are just I don't
want to say just cuz again that sounds
crazy but you are just a performing
Premier League player and you will be
that
>> triple pay.
>> Yeah. Yeah. you will be that for the
rest of your career like just Prem level
like but I don't think
>> and I don't think he even thinks it like
that he's oh okay I'm going to go off
again and go back to Arsenal I'm going
to go to city I'm going to go no you
will be Fulham and these teams but
>> mate you're going to be that's that's a
great career at the end of the day you
mean I see that I think that's the same
for Drewsby Hall even though he did drop
down to the championship but yeah I
think that's way too good for the German
>> but that whole team was Anton Stack at
Leads Leads
have a physical team. He's good. Do you
I was looking at it this morning. He's
sprinted. He's ran
>> more than anyone in the league.
>> Like full stop.
>> I haven't really paid attention to this
guy.
>> So he's Oh, I was trying to find like
cuz I was wondering how like how many
sprints and stuff he's done. He's sort
of Yeah. hardworking midfielder, a big
boy. Um 6'2. Um and that that's what
leads have kind of gone down that road.
Like you can tell Danny Foggles are
really big on like let's not get bullied
at least. Um and like uh Lang Stuff as
well. Long stuff. Long stuff. Long
stuff. Long stuff.
>> Sean Long Staff. Yeah. Scored a kind of
fortunate goal the weekend. But yeah, I
he makes them really really solid. Uh
he's got slight Pinia vibes as well. I
think he's I I'll take this one. I think
he's um
>> he I think he's huge cuz I think
literally he's huge, but also he's 26.
So I think he will be Premier. He'll be
a triple P by the end of the
>> Premier League player.
>> I like it when you phrase the board. uh
he will be a triple P by the end of the
season. So again, if if it does if you
aren't able to get it done, it's not one
where like you're going to be you'd
either love him in the Championship,
which I don't think he would need to do.
Um and it' be interesting if Lead is
going to stay up. Like they they look
solid.
>> The three promoter teams have been a lot
better than I thought.
>> Yeah. And technically, he's pretty good
as well. I think it'll be one by the end
of the season, I think there'll be a lot
of talk about him. I think he's been
amazing, a really solid signing for them
so far from what I've seen.
>> Uh here we go. Florian Verts
I just see. Oh no, he's got an assist.
He's got assist. He's got
>> assist. Florian verts. This one is
>> you know Florian.
>> I went big on this guy. I kept saying I
go he's he's you've bought a Premier
League great.
>> Yeah. Wow. Wow. I didn't I didn't go
that far. No.
>> I'm holding firm. I think
>> I'm a fan of Florian BS. I'm not going
to flip-flop. I'm not going to switch up
now. But I I am a little even though
I've used to watch him at Le Vusen, but
again it all depends on the league
you're in and stuff like that. But I am
startled. I'm getting a little bit
scared with how physically weak he is.
>> I'm like you are getting pushed off. You
>> think he's that physically weak?
>> He's getting pushed off the ball like
and he's not listen
right but he found he used to know how
to shield the ball, keep the ball away
from you, use your body. I'm looking at
Verts and I'm like, "Bro, you're
literally just like telling them come
get the ball off me." And they're just
pushing you off the ball and he's not
bursting past players. And I'm like,
"Don't. You're giving me a Sancho vibes
quite early on, man. You're giving me
Sancho vibes right now." So,
>> sure, man.
>> So, I'm going to say he will come good
because again, I will be seriously
flip-flopping if I just turn around now.
>> So, why did you like him? Answer that.
>> I I love intelligence.
>> I love um people that have like good
first touches, you know what I mean? His
incisive dribbling is is brilliant and
one thing I always thought was
underrated about him is that is his
shooting ability. I think a lot of
people I think Prem fans honestly have
misprofiled him a little bit. I was
seeing Prem fans talking about him like
coming to the club and they were talking
about him a little bit in a way that in
a like in a silver ozil kind of vibe
where they were like oh we're going to
get this like playmaker who's going to
be and I was like he for for me he feels
a lot more of like a shooter a lot more
of like a more creative than a Phil
Foden
>> but more on that kind of kind of path
where Fod score yeah dribble line score
shoot
>> and I was hearing People would talk like
he's going to be this kind of like ball
dominant kind of and I was like you're
getting the you're getting the wrong
player here. You know what I mean? He's
not that type of player. So
>> I think he was already misprofiled from
the start. So the the exaggeration
around his performances are there
because people have to overcompensate
always happens.
>> But
I think he will come good.
>> But my butts with him is what is good?
Because we have to be honest, 116
million.
>> Yeah.
>> What we how he was spoken about before
signing good for me is like
he has to be as you you said Premier
League great. Like he has to be like one
of the he has to be one of the best
players in the Premier League.
>> I don't know. I'm scared about that a
little bit, but I don't think he I think
he'll come good. But will he ever live
James? Would he ever live to to his 116
million price tag?
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. He's going to be there a long
time.
>> Okay.
>> So, yes, he is. I think a few things.
First of all, I was just trying to find
it and I'm not good enough on the Excel
spreadsheet to to do it properly, but
I've got he's made
he's made 108
sprints.
>> I used to see these stats for me oil
man.
>> Right. No. And bear with me with this
like and I'm I'm looking around and I'm
seeing I'm not seeing a lot. Name
another player because I'm having to do
it through fire. Never know a player who
should be similar role as Vert.
>> Um
similar role.
>> Oh, my mind's gone blank. Um well, he's
talking about like a number 10.
>> Yeah. Trying to think. So, let's say um
it's hard cuz who's played every single
game. I was going to say someone like
Kuna or something like that, but he
wouldn't. He hasn't played every single
game. Look,
>> number 10. Yeah, number 10's in the game
these days. Ezra,
right? Don't worry about that. The point
is, the point is a lot of players um
very few players are making that amount
of runs. I think
>> is that good for him though?
>> No.
>> No. I think when you think of Vert
>> Mhm.
>> you're thinking of a 10. Are you When
you're thinking of a 10, are you
thinking of someone running in behind?
>> No,
>> you're not. You're not.
>> I think And look, who am I? Right. I
think Anna Slot knows far more about
football than I do, right? and he's got
to find what works for for Liverpool
right now. I feel like he's not the
aside yet.
>> Yep. I agree.
>> Right. And so you've kind of and if you
think of how they're playing, Ekit looks
great. Right. Echo is doing what he
>> Well, one of the several skills that
he's really good at, but in terms of
like him dropping in, pick up the ball
and then knitting it together and then
going,
>> the reason he's able to kind of do that
and it work is Vert is running be past
him a lot of the time. where at leakm
that whole team was set up to give him
the ball.
>> He doesn't get the ball. He's not
getting the ball the same amount in my
opinion. He's not being able to like
stand there and people zip it into him.
He's having to go and get it when he
does go and get it.
>> So I don't I feel like that team is
still working to ideally work for the
you know Ekit so far. get Salah on the
ball at the end of it all. Yeah.
>> Or you've obviously got gakpo on the
other side as well, so he needs to get
him involved. He's probably gonna want
to come inside as well. So that's kind
of your space again as well.
>> So I think currently he's not the team's
not set up in a way that where it's all
about him just yet. I wonder
>> with this coming through the door,
>> I think this could be a real season of
struggle for him.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> I think next season, certainly the
season after that, if you know, if the
belief is stays with him, which I don't
think it should go away too far.
>> Salah won't be there forever. Yeah.
>> And I think when that changes, I think
you can it can be far more about him.
But right now, it's just not about him
for enough. So, he's having to do things
>> he doesn't really want to do.
>> Yeah. That's the thing. When some
players go to clubs,
>> you become you are the system and then
you become a cog in the system. And when
with somebody that throw in verse now,
he's just a cog in many moving pieces.
And it's like how do you match up to
that? And but the greats find a way. I
always think about like Gareth Bale when
he went to Real Madrid from what he was
at Spurs, he was the system, but then he
goes to Real Madrid, there's Cristiano
there, there's all these players,
>> but he's so good that he still found a
way of playing. But if you look at the
way he played at Real Madrid to the way
he played at Tottenham in the final few
seasons at Tottenham, it's a completely
different player. It's genuinely a
complete
type of players because Salah's a legend
of the game, but he has to if you're
Vert, you're a record signing, you have
to walk in there, look Salah in the eye
and be like, "Hey, we're it's a a and yo
a some days I'm a some days you're a but
I don't think he's walked in there with
that at the moment." And now you're
looking at it and I'm like, is he in
Liverpool's best 11 right now?
>> I wouldn't say so. I look at the
midfield, Shabbos, Mallister, Graham
Burch, and on the left hand side, Gako
has been moved out because they're
trying to incorporate um uh Vertz. And
you're thinking even in their strongest
team, maybe Akit might be on the left
now or EAC. We they're going to have to
find a way of making that work.
>> But at the moment, I'm thinking off the
left, no, not really. In the middle, no.
So now you've got 116 million pound
player that's coming off the bench. But
You got to commit in that stock. You got
to commit to that stock for me. So I was
just trying I was just trying to find
someone else there. Like I'm not
different teams maybe playing slightly
differently.
>> Josh King I was thinking like you know
he's a 10.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> How many sprints do you think he's
making?
>> How much did you say Vert has made?
>> 108.
>> Josh King he kind of runs a lot. I'm
going to say he's made
>> 90.
>> 67.
>> Wow.
>> Now look then maybe not got the ball as
much.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. But I I think it's worth I think
it's worth sort of saying. How many's
ech made?
>> Oh,
the Liverpool team 80
>> 64.
>> Oh man.
>> So your striker your striker's not doing
that and V is doing 108.
>> Yeah, that's crazy.
>> So I think there's something in that. I
really do.
>> And you look at the type player he is.
That's a lot of
>> like he's not powerful. So him having to
sprint that much and it's that could
affect his game 100%. That could affect
him.
>> I think it'll come good. Yeah, I'll put
him as will come good. I just don't know
how good the good is, but I'll put him
as will come good because he's a quality
player.
>> Yeah, here is we've got them together.
Who who will play more games this
season?
>> Hey Isach, you better watch out. You
know, you better watch out. You better
watch out. Um I
I think they have to make Isach play.
But I was saying, now everyone that
watched my content would know. I was
saying Isak's a huge signing, but it's a
I'm feeling very greedy today, so I'm
just gonna add something on top of my
meal that I don't really need. Do you
know what I mean? And I said by the end
of the season, we could have easily been
speaking about Akitique the way we speak
about Isak. Isak have had two 20 goal
seasons, right, in the Premier League.
>> I think Akitake can do that. I've been
so impressed
>> at the end of the season he could score
25 goals for Liverpool all comps and we
will be speaking about him in the same
breath as Isak qualitywise is there much
difference quality I think there's
similar levels of quality maybe you
could say Isak is
>> a bit more refined and stuff more out
feel well certainly with the way they're
playing I could take his players back to
goal a lot more who is complete in a
different way but probably wants to face
the goal a bit more
>> Isak is very good at against the best
center halfs He's given them lots of
trouble. So, Isak is probably the better
player at the moment. By the end of the
season, we could have been speaking
about Ekit like Isak. Now, I do think
and it's a lovely lovely issue to have,
I guess, but there is a little bit there
will be a little bit I think of a little
bit of issues there because they're
they're both too good to sit on the
bench. Especially how Ekk started firing
before Isa even got his move. He's at
came and he's still firing and then he's
going to have to be like I saw the other
day he scored a brace and then he came
off 67 minutes or something that's
that's removed him from getting a
hat-tick potentially. You know, these
are little things as a striker you're
going to be like keep having to and how
often in the 4-33 era with a one man up
top. Yeah. Not not not two strikers, one
man up top. Have you had two top
strikers stay at the club together for a
long time? You don't get it.
>> One of these two will be gone in two
years.
>> One of these two gone two, three years.
>> Just to check it out there, you know,
because we were talking about Verts and
like with the pressure for him to work.
>> Yeah.
>> If Echertica and Vertz don't really kind
of find a flow together as a pairing
because it feels like Vert is being like
quite sacrificial with all of it. Isach
might if to it's maybe an easier life if
you
>> move ech aside
>> to allow Isach to play more as like an
out andout striker and then you give
verts that space to go and do that. So
that might make life difficult for ek
but if he's playing too good he's
playing too good.
>> Yeah that affects but then that affects
like a mallistister or a shabosi and
then all of a sudden the balance of the
team
>> which will go is a little bit of a
headache. Which one will go?
>> Which one? Okay. Which one of those
three were the first to leave the club?
>> Ekit.
>> Yeah,
>> cuz I think he's going to do well.
>> Yes. I think he's going to do so well,
but always because of the fee and
because of who Isizak is, might not get
the nod. And then there's going to be a
big team like a Barcelona who are
looking for strikers. There's going to
be a team is I mean Ekit will just take
him.
>> There we go. So, and that's all three
are quality players, but I think you
this is what happens with squads, you
know? It's just what happens. Like, it's
okay to have Erling Harland if your
second striker is Jesus. No disrespect.
It's okay to have this. Yeah, but but
these two I'm telling you, Ekkit can
look this guy in the eye and it's going
to and that's not that's not good, you
know? It's not a good thing. Like,
Alvarez, look what happened with him.
Like,
>> said this to me. He said, "When like
every every year you like there'd be
free strikers and like I hate you."
>> Yeah. You I Well, I'm worried about you
two cuz you're trying to take my spot.
>> The third choice is like he hates him
because he wants the second spot so he
can get close to me. You hate me like
>> Yeah. And Alvarez, Julian Alvarez at Man
City, he got to a point where it's like
he's too good just to be some sub
player. Athletic just sniffed that
straight away.
>> Thank you very much. And I think that's
what could happen. Milos Kirk nine
appearances,
>> n uh 0.73 crosses into the penalty area
in 2425, 0.2 two in 25 26 I
>> I'm not sure they're having him you know
but
>> he what's really unfair on KZ
>> what's really unfair on KZ is
Arlaw and this is and Arnos manager he
needs to win the game so that's all he's
got to do right it's fine
>> but he is playing him a lot more narrow
or he he goes up and pretends he's being
a 10 but the whole every person on that
pitch knows they're never going to pass
the ball to him and and Kirk himself his
body language. He's going
>> pointing at the other guy, so you don't
want the ball.
>> Yeah.
>> And that's not the best of Kirk, right?
>> The best of Kirk was him being dynamic
and everyone was raving about him.
Defensively, he's a little bit erratic.
>> Very
>> right. But in terms of getting back, he
can do that. He's got, you know, he's
obviously physically more impressive
than Andy Robertson right now. But I was
watching the game against Palace and and
he's like when he Yeah. when they have
got the ball, he either got out the way
so Mallister could drop in and get the
ball
>> or he was kind of there in a really safe
place.
>> So either way, you're not getting the
best version of Kirk. Now, is that
>> is that a problem broadly? No. You know,
Liverpool's still been winning winning
games,
>> but if you've bought Kirz and you want
the bulm, you're not you're not going to
get him.
>> Yeah. And I think that's a problem for
the uh the optics of Kirz. I also there
are moments where and maybe it's just
this one game and I was looking at I
sort of saw it and I was like I feel
like I'm seeing something here.
>> They didn't want to pass to him. It
didn't feel like or sorry it wasn't
that. It was more like
>> it was more like this sounds really
harsh but it's like why would I pass to
you when Mallister's there or it was
more that
>> Yeah.
>> And um
>> and I don't know. I don't know.
>> Respecting these I'm going to put not
quite feeling. I don't like the start.
Um I still think at this point I don't
know. I think Robinson might still be
the best better left back at this point.
So I wonder if
>> I'm not sure but maybe it's a bad just a
rough start but
>> I'm not I'm not feeling it. I'm afraid
and I do wonder the one thing also when
Fong comes see that's the thing I think
about next year you think at some point
Salah will go.
>> Yeah. and Frim Pong will take that space
and that might you know alleviate a lot
of these different things. I also wonder
if you bring in a if you have Mark Gay
and Van Djk there is that one where you
go okay we're right you can go now
>> so that the fullback's a little bit more
and that might lead to something because
there's definitely moments where you'd
go on go.
>> Yeah
>> and uh he's not and I feel like that
there's a reason for that. I think he's
you know abiding instructions.
>> I feel for Liverpool's fullbacks. They
had two legendary fullbacks in Brao and
Trent who were the system under Klo in
their best years. Those two were the
system. Like the midfield three, you
guys were literally there to basically
cover spaces for them to to get forward
and they were putting record numbers of
assists up and stuff like that. So now
you go to these guys who are not
legendary players. Fong and and Kirz,
it's a
>> it maybe can be seen as a a downgrade,
which is
>> so different, aren't they? I do I think
I'm wrong about Fong. I said something
about like he'd be a bit of a flop about
I I think I'd change my mind cuz I think
I think he's exciting once he's on the
pitch. Do you know what I mean?
>> I guess so. I haven't really seen too
much yet, but I like Ring Pong to be
fair.
>> We'll do a few more and then we'll do a
quick fire bunch if that's okay. So, uh
I mean this might be an easy quick one.
Uh Rinders.
>> Oh yeah, huge
>> proper player. Proper player Rind is in
it. And the thing is his engine is very
underrated as well. I didn't know he had
an engine like that. I knew he was a
very good player. Got an eye for goal.
His engine he gets about man. He
>> and it's like a quiet like it's quite
electric car you know. He's just going
>> but it's not it's some players you watch
you see him run and you can hear the
>> he's not really it's like one of those
quiet ones.
>> He's Yeah, he's
>> um Brian and Burmo
>> will come good.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Cuz yeah, I wanted to get your take on
the Man United guys.
>> He will come good. I I I really like
Embuo, but you know with the Amarim
situation, I'm not liking the positions
that he's taking up on the pitch. He's
nowhere near close enough to goal, which
is really annoying because when he was
at Brenford, he was close to goal. When
you look at with Ivan Tony or with
Whissa, that's why they had this great
one-two punch and now we've just got him
on the touch line, which he's meant to
be in the 10, but he's not a 10. And
then we've got him on the touch line
just spamming crosses to only one man in
the box. We only have one man in box
with Cesco. So he's looking pretty
wasteful but I believe in him. I think
he's a good player. So he will come and
I know Kuna is the next one.
>> Yep.
>> He's in the exact same boat for me. Kuna
I'm a little bit a little bit more
concerned than I am with Embumo because
Kuna has given me as I said hero of a
slow you know when they say big fish
small pond I don't look at Embumo like
that. I look at him as a you can plug
and play him. I can imagine him going
into Liverpool Arsenal plug and play
type player. But I look at Kuna and I
think are you a are you the system type
player? Like are you the player that
needs the system around you? And that's
where I'm kind of like are you ever
going to have that at Man United? Kind
of just what you're saying about Verts.
Are you going to have that? Now you're a
quality player with Bruno about and just
in general like so I'm looking at and
I'm thinking
>> to get that you're going to have to come
in and do massive things. So instantly
we're like okay this needs to be Kuna's
team and right now hasn't been the way
so far but he's a quality player. So,
I'm going to say will come good as well,
but I have a little bit more concern
than I do formo.
>> Yeah, I I agree on both. Maybe even huge
for uh is itumo? I was going
>> I used to say Bumo, right? And everyone
started saying I was saying it wrong and
then he did a thing and he said his name
was Umbumo.
>> Yeah,
>> Impumo at the Premier League. I swear I
got told it was in Burma. So, I shook
out Burma.
>> That's what I'm saying. I don't know,
man.
>> I think he could be huge cuz I think his
goals might keep him up.
>> Who's
you want to call it? Brian,
>> honestly could if he gets that bad. Uh
>> Nick Volultard,
>> I like him. You know,
>> new Crouchy.
>> Got the touch of crouch. He's got the
silk.
>> 23, man. Great.
>> I like him, you know. I like him. And
you know what? I'm going to say huge.
You know what I'm going to say? Huge.
>> Now, I don't hope Man United fans don't
think I'm not saying that Kuna and Buma
are huge players. They are huge players,
but I think we're so bad right now. So,
I need to say we'll come good. Anyway,
back to Volt Mada, right? I think he's
going to be a huge sign and because of
the context as well, I think losing
Isach was like that must have been
deflated.
>> He's hit the ground running. That's
crucial, don't they?
>> Yes. But I think he's going to kind of
just
>> Hey, life is not so doom and gloom
without Isach. You know, Vissa will come
back. He'll run a little big man's
little man thing. You know, we used to
see it back in Defo and Crouchy. Hey,
run it back, man. You know, Eddie How,
man. Hey, run it back. So, I I like the
signing. I'm going to say I'm going to
say it's going to be a huge signing.
>> Okay. And the last one on United, uh
Ses,
>> what I It's been hard, man, considering
you were like waiting to see him and now
you're starting to see him.
>> Yeah. It's s I actually looking at him
and I'm like, "Okay, in a few of your
moments, you look good. Like, I'm seeing
your touches are are decent. You're
working the back four. You're not going
to get any service." The thing about it
is that you're going to have to create
your own goals at Man United. Honestly,
like the the difference with him and
Hyland is that he actually can control
the like Hyand was not controlling the
ball. He was battling and losing out.
Cesco, I saw like he won his flick on
against Chelsea. He's like he's a bit
more of a presence. So, I like him. But
honestly, with Man United number nine, I
can never ever predict it. It's like I
don't I wish there was another section
where you could just say like unknown.
>> Yeah,
>> cuz like
I don't know.
>> You're scared. I
>> I'm going to say he's going to will come
good.
>> Yeah.
>> In the imagination that we get a new
manager.
>> I think he'll come good, mate. Don't
worry.
>> Yeah, I think you're right. I think he's
got everything you need. Yeah. All
right. Let's do quicker.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Ready?
>> Dan and Doy.
>> This is a This is a Forest
>> will come good.
>> I see. I think huge. I think I think
they've done well there. I don't think
they've actually dropped off at all. I
think he's as good as Alanganger
actually the more I think about it.
Hhabib Diara don't if you see much of
him Sunderland
>> I haven't seen too much.
>> He will.
>> People have been talking about him a lot
I think this year.
>> Okay.
>> The one thing he does and this is where
I disagree with me and Kai disagree with
him. He shoots a lot
>> really
>> and I think that could lead to a couple
of like bangers and it will work for you
and it'll be fine but sometimes it's
like you don't need to always shoot. You
know what player remember was like that
QPR
>> who'd always shoot
>> in the Premier League
>> in the Prem. Christ
>> always true and you're like what are you
doing but then he caught one banger one
time and I was like FZ who
>> danger
against Arsenal
>> bro he would shoot and you're like you
haven't got the tech for it why are you
shooting like his light eyes will light
up at any shooting opportunity you know
when fans say shoot he took it literally
but then yeah he got that finally he
finally got that banger
>> um so D I think I think He's huge and
he's both of these are huge but that's
what they they they sort of sing
together for me.
>> Diara Granite Jhaka
>> he they're building it's built around
him with the profiles around him that
will work for him that provide the legs
that he need. He just needs to be smart
on the ball and god he is.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I'm going to watch out for
him now. I'm going to keep attention.
Yeah.
>> Robin as well is another one. Uh he's
the goalkeeper had a great start to the
season as well. Uh and and and um yeah
won't will come good. He's come good
already. Jia,
>> did you say Granite Shaka?
>> I had said Granite Shaka.
>> Oh, that's my favorite sign in the
summer.
>> Is it?
>> That is the one that I said.
>> What's the difference between him and
Endo?
>> And who?
>> Naka
has got more quality for me. Shaka, that
is the signing of the season. I'm
telling you, I loved it from the minute
it happened. The type of player he is,
warrior, absolute warrior, leader,
experience, got on ball quality as well,
which he's shown already. He got some
clutch assists. This guy is a is I
always thought he's a really good
player. I've always loved Shaka and for
him to walk in I love that Sunland
instantly just said here's the armband.
We're not wasting any time. Take it take
us to the promised land as well. Arsenal
said you know Arsenal said he can do it.
>> Instantly going to be like it I I I said
at the start of season
>> he it's going to take one to three games
for him to be a cult hero at Sunderland
and it's happened already for me. I've
got two signings that I absolutely love
and he's that's that's one of them.
>> Okay, let's see if there's one of the
other ones. Jia,
>> uh I think it's a good signing. Not
huge, but we'll come good.
>> Semi feeling it. Javi Simmons,
>> I don't know if this one. It's Techi,
but he's been looking all right. He
looked all right, and he was terrible
against um who was the last game they
played, the 1-1.
>> Uh Wolves.
>> Wolves. Yeah, I'm going to say will come
good, but I don't think his level is
going to be like unbelievable. I think
it's just going to be a good player like
Madison was good in it. He was good.
Yeah.
>> Okay. Kudos
>> will come good.
>> I think huge.
>> Huge. No, no, you could huge.
>> Yeah,
>> huge.
>> I get sort of like you're waiting for
him to grab his career.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Uh Elaz Malik Jof,
>> my favorite signing. That's the next Is
that the other one?
>> That's the next one.
>> What a player, man.
>> Yeah,
>> this guy is proper. I don't care. This
is one and done.
>> This is one and done, James.
>> What do you mean?
>> One and done in terms of He will not be
at West Ham next season.
>> Oh, okay.
>> One and done. He can play for everybody.
>> I love the way he hits a cross.
>> His bro, has he got the his whips are
unbelievable. And I saw it against
England against Senagal England. And I
was like, who is this left back? He
looks unbelievable. One of my friends
like, yeah, Joff, he's gone to West Ham.
So I was like, "Okay, that's going to be
my one to watch signing of the season."
And already he's showing what he can do.
Honestly, he looks above West Ham's
level. You look at Man City right now,
they got Nori, he's okay. He's good.
Yeah. You look at United, Duo. He's he's
all right. You look at these teams, Kirk
was just talking about, he can play for
anybody, I think.
>> Player, man. 20
and what Senagal are going to have a
great World Cup as well. So,
>> okay. Lots of predictions there. Uh, and
that's the end of it.
>> Great work. Well done. We've judged
enough people now, haven't we? I think
enough's enough.
>> One more.
>> Oh, you got one more. Go and chuck it.
>> Ryan Shy,
>> of course. Yeah.
>> Will come good.
>> Yeah.
>> Watch.
>> I got a lot of the line for that one. We
got
>> Is he your boy or is he his boy first?
>> So, Leah had the Algerian connection.
So, that was his boy from like from day
one. But then like when I saw Shery, I
just fell in love with this guy.
Honestly, I've got a lot right. If he
flops, yo, I might have to go into
hiding. You know that. Yo, I think it
Again, it's one is he you're not going
to build the systems around him though,
are they?
>> They're not. They won't. Man City won't
do that. They do that. So, he'll have to
find a way. But he is so talented. It's
just
>> he he makes you enjoy watching football.
>> Oh my god, bro. Like, he is just he's so
special. So, I just hope it works out.
>> Me and Le joke about this like we joke
about this phrase. It's called a court
to lose, which means lights out. She's
basically a dummy.
>> Okay.
>> Right. And so when you're talking about
like relationism, right, when you hear
that sort of spoken, the quarter lo is
used a lot because if you're sort of
coming and defending, if the pass is
coming here and you def the defender has
to come to you.
>> But if you just leave the ball and it
goes behind you, that player's out, but
that player had to come to you because
what if you touch it, then you've not,
you know, you're not tight enough. So a
quarter is a really powerful thing that
I don't think people use enough in in
modern football. So when you kind of see
it, you're like like and um and Ryan
Chery loves it. So whenever I see one or
whenever I see one with Ryan Chuggy in
particular cuz he did a couple in the
Club World Cup when we were doing it for
Dar
I'll always just send it to him but he
loves it especially with Harland. He
loves a little like little dummy.
>> Oh he he's such a But honestly though
listen let him get back from his injury.
I hate when my favorite players play for
the rivals but
>> hey it is what it is. Turkey we got a
lot riding for you mate.
>> Lots of players will come good. That's
the positivity we're trying to put out.
So good luck to everyone. We didn't say
no refund, did we?
>> No, we didn't. Cuz I don't think we were
able to get a full refund on
>> certain refund on anyone that I'm
thinking of. Have you got any refunds on
M? That wasn't on the list.
>> Refunds.
>> The only one. Yeah, I guess Pellini have
not bought him, have you? It's just a
loan. So that's So that is you can get a
solid refund there. Um because it's not
cost you anything. Um I don't know ones
that you're not There's a few that
>> refund. Refund one.
>> Who's in the league at the moment?
>> I do. I want Yakarez to do well. You
just
>> you put him in the refund.
>> No, but like you just sort of wonder a
little bit, don't you? You do wonder,
but I think it's an aesthetic thing.
>> I think that's the big thing here.
Right. Here we go.
>> These are the 10 top 10 this summer.
>> Which one do you need? Would you if you
if you had to get a refund from one of
these? Okay, you could get a refund and
it doesn't exist. That transfer's done.
All right. All right. Yarez, Dubendi,
>> Ez,
>> Kuna,
>> Voltoada,
and Bumo,
>> Bumo,
>> Seso.
>> Mhm.
>> Ech,
you might be a good dude. You know,
>> you were a good dude, but that's a
that's a that was a British record
transfer. Could Liverpool reinvest that
money? Is Vert gonna be 116 million
pound signing?
>> When do you need to get the payoff?
That's the question. If you've got five
years to get the payoff,
>> I'm not so sure.
>> Not so sure.
>> I got to go for the most pricey pricey
ones, you know. So,
>> verse.
>> Yeah, cuz I think Isak is going to be
still be special.
>> I think mine's Yokarez, you know.
>> Yarez is Yakist.
>> Yeah. Sorry. I am struggling with the
>> care is up there,
>> right?
>> Yeah, your career is up there.
>> Let us know yours in the comments.
>> Fascinating question. Only you can
provide the answer. Let us know in the
comments. Follow this podcast. Go listen
to all the previous editions. They're
all wonderful and evergreen. Go and
subscribe and watch all of Cam's
content, every single one. And do not
skip any of the ads. Get our boys some
bag. Um, enjoy yourself. Have a great
week and we'll speak soon.