Right people, welcome back to the ripple
effect. I am joined by Cams Culture.
Cams is here.
Good to be back. Good. Yeah, man. I'm
buzzing. I'm buzzing to be here, man.
On on the best of
um moments, let's say, cuz we're going
to get I said to you, do we go through
the Man United stuff or do we talk
broader?
And you were like, let's get this out of
the way.
Let's get out the way. Just
get the pain out the way.
Yeah, man. Get out the way and then I'm
warm onto the next one. You know what I
mean?
Nice one. So, what we're going to do is
we're going to be ranking Man United
departures, but they get progressively
worse. So, big talking point has been
what seems to happen with these players
where they they leave and then do a
little bit better. We'll get into that
and we've got a list of sort of the most
painful ones and I I've got some tiers
for you. So, in terms of how I want you
to rank them, I kind of want you to
describe the level of pain of their
departure.
Okay.
Oh, departure. Okay.
Yes. Okay.
Because I think these players leaving
and then doing well.
Yeah. It's easy to have that hindsight
of why did we let that person go? And I
think in some of these it's legitimate,
but some of them it's not as well.
Yeah.
But I guess to to provide the context
before that, we have to talk about the
present day
and obviously the defeat against
Brenford, which is not the first ever
defend uh defeat by Man United of
Brenford at Griffin Park. It's not park,
is it? Where is it? The community
stadium now.
Yeah. G2. I think that's I've always had
one of my sort of like theories is that
okay losing and building pressure is one
thing. People don't like losing to
Brenford.
Like if you're a manager under pressure,
one don't play Brenford because they'll
be well drilled.
Yeah.
But like secondly, don't lose because
the sort of media fallout is
is pretty heavy now
you from what I've seen you were pretty
early on Amarim.
Very early. Make sure you tell them
that.
Another line I've got is if you want to
be right, be a pessimist.
No. Is that you know what? Do you know
what
what's what's your general describe
yourself as a Man United fan? What one
are you?
You know what? I'm very like I'm I'm in
between. When I'm excited, I will lead
an army of excitement. Like I will I I
make catchphrases. I make slogans. We're
doing this together. Do you know what I
mean? I'm telling you, every manager I
have supported in the beginning heavily
like heavily. But I am very quick like
because
when I watch the game I try and watch it
not in the lens of a Man United fan
because I tend to Yeah. Because
no it's not possible in not possible
when you're going through the motions.
for example, Leon game. There's no way I
can sit there like when it happened. I
wasn't going to be like, well, I'm not
happy with how
Yeah, you're buzzing. I'm going crazy.
Even though I know like, okay, the game
shouldn't have gone that way. But
I tend to realize that opposition fans
or rival fans are much quicker on the
Man United situation than than us fans.
The truth.
Yeah. Exactly. The truth. So, I try and
like watch it kind of away, kind of like
an analyst in a way, and I very quickly
see patterns where I'm like, "Oh, okay."
So, then I kind of like warn the fan
base like, "Yo, I'm not liking what I'm
seeing." And then, you know, that's when
everyone says, "Oh, you're a fake fan."
Blah, blah, blah. But I never want to be
right with these type of things. Never,
ever, ever, ever. Because like being
happy, I haven't been happy as a Man
United fan properly for ye for 10 over
10 years. So, I want to be buzzing
since Fergie. What's the happiest you've
been?
You know, I was thinking about this the
other day actually. Me and my boys are
talking about it. I would say there's a
few phases.
When Jose came in, I was like, we're
back. Like, Jose Marino, you crazy.
So, that was a good moment. When he
initially came,
interim period
was honestly I think that might be up
there. I think his interim period before
he signed the dotted line PSG like
Cardiff all them games that was
unbelievable and then I won't I would
say Tenhog's first season up until the
Caribel up before the 7-0 of Liverpool
right
up until the Caribel Cup win.
There was a little moment in the season
where I was like we could actually we're
in a title race here like if we win our
next game we we're going to be level
with Arsenal. I was starting to believe
honestly. So I would say those moments
lockdown after lockdown was pretty cool
as well cuz we finished second on with
Ollie as well. There's been a few times
where you're like buzzing but
it's just never enough is it? It's just
never enough.
I think this is a really good context to
to sort of highlight because
part of
the desire to keep Amarim in the job.
Yeah.
I think I think if you swap him
for before Mourinho
Mhm.
like he's gone, isn't he?
100%. the context is saving has has
saved him up to this point. Probably
I I I feel like other managers failing
Yeah. has allowed him to get more time
because, you know, we're in that boat
where it's like, well, you've sacked so
many managers, so it's never worked, so
why is this one going to work? But
for me, that's not the mentality to
have. And as you said, you know, a lot
of people are trying to say, oh, he's
the worst manager since Moyes. He's way
worse than David Moyes. Like it's
actually disrespectful to David Moyes
that he's being bunched with with Amarim
in terms of results and how it's going
at United. And I think with David Moyes
anyway, I think he was in a most every
single manager that's been in charge. I
think he was in the toughest position.
Who but who had a who had a better
squad? David Moyes or
I would probably say R. Um I would say
David Moyes had a better score. I mean
we just came off winning the title now.
Players were aging. Rio was old. Vidic
was old. Evra was old. Giggs was old.
Um, who else was there? Rooney was
starting to get on Van Percy. So, it was
an aging squad, but there was still like
Nanny, Chicherito, and Carics and stuff
like that. So, he definitely had a
better squad. He had winners as well.
Cuz I think that's part of the part of
the cycle here.
Mhm. is that
like first of all a load of different
managers, a load of different managers
bringing in their guys. the pressure on
those guys which gonna we're going to
see like the relief of that pressure and
what that provides in a second
and then the change of manager who
always has so much pressure on them kind
of kind of understand it would be
because you saw what worked with Fergie
but in the modern game
that manager being given that much
y
uh say in in transfers and things like
that has led to like the squad quality
dropping and dropping less people want
to come to you they want to go to other
places and it like it's a sort of you're
swirling down a bit of a drain of
quality
because it's getting so kind of confused
and then
cuz this is the thing that
that's going to be weird if Amarim goes
is that
it's the it's October, November, Dece.
It's the same period. It feels like
there are these P and that's going to
lead to a new manager coming in not with
a squad that he wants. Mhm.
So that's a bit of an excuse and it's
going to take time
and all those things and you're just
going to create the same cycle.
Yeah. The thing is I'm kind of like look
I know one thing that I feel like nobody
factors in when it comes to Man United
or playing at the top level is the
mental side. You know you just look at
like
the on paper you looking at players but
mental side is different. So, I don't
want to use this comparison, but like
you do look at David Moyes, you do look
at Glasgner, you know, go into these
clubs and instantly just getting a bit
of stability and their teams are able to
build from there cuz once you build a
little bit of stability, everything else
moves from there. And I think that's
what Glazner did, that's what ever um
David Moyes did with Everton now. Much
bigger club, much bigger ask. But I do
think sometimes it's a bit overblown
that like a manager has to come in, need
his own players, need his own I don't
think that necessarily has to be the
case. I think good managers will walk
in, stabilize the team and then
gradually start implementing their thing
gradually. But the most important thing
is you walk in and say I want results.
And I feel too many times
that Amarim said that. I think Am I
think Amarim say that I think Am
honestly when I look back Yeah. because
I listened to Amarim's press conferences
initially and I was like excited for him
but when I look back of course he said
the whole famous we must suffer but away
from that he was kind of telling us in a
way like if we lose we lose like as long
as I implement my way of playing. But I
wasn't really catching that at the time.
Now I'm looking back and I'm like to be
fair he's been saying that the whole
time. We're going to lose but it doesn't
mean it's acceptable. You know what I
mean? I need a manager. I'm
sure he said we need to I I need to win.
I need to come in and win. I'm I'm sure
he said that as well. But I think that's
the thing. There's there's the sort of
um overcorrection. There could be a lot
of overcorrections with managers and and
with tenh it was like I'm not I don't
know what you're trying to do here.
Right.
Yeah. And so you brought in a guy who
said he he knows exactly what he's going
to do, but it feels like he's only got
one kind of answer.
And the thing is every top coach, Pep
Guardiola, Jose Fergie, everyone that
you can name have tried different
things. So that's the point where I'm
like it can't only be stemming from Am.
It has to also be stemming from above as
well in terms of for him to just
casually say not even the Pope can make
me change my form or my system. I'm like
I mean to have the freedom to just say
that and no pressure from above to be
like okay slow down a little bit it's
it's crazy to me. So as much as I blame
him you've got to look above as well. Do
you know what I mean? Cuz I just
Pep Guardiola changes up.
Fergie changes up. Like I remember going
to away games in Europe and Ferguson
will play 451 4-33 back to the Premier
League 442. It it doesn't matter like
and it's a lot of people are caught on
the formation. It's the system. Glazner
plays the same formation but the system
is completely different. He midfield
progression etc. So
I just think there's a lot of arrogance
coming from from Amarim but I also think
he doesn't
is it arrogance or is it do you think
there's a bit
yeah often I you know there's nothing
wrong with faking it till you make it.
Do you think it do you think that an
element of that ele I think I'm
experienced I'm ready. Oh no like this
is this is different. I think he's
afraid that if he switches up, he loses
all sense of power that he has at this
football club.
But
management is about adapting. You know
what I mean? Management is coaching.
If he comes and goes, "Right, back for
like change."
True change.
You'd be like, "Love that. Good man.
Right. Let's stick with him now."
I will give him extra time. I would I
would I would give him if he says,
"Look, boom, we go to Sunderland on the
weekend."
How big is that?
And it's a that's I think that's not
looking good. That's I'm telling you I'm
looking at that Sunderland team.
Every game looks hard, doesn't it, when
it's not going well?
Every game they got good they've got a
good team. Underrated team, you know,
like you got Isidador up front. He's a
problem. You got Mki, the new signing,
Granite Shaka. Granite Shaka. These
players start from
Sadiki and Diara. The way they set up
it. It gets the best. It's I think
there's a phrase that people are
chugging out there a lot which is called
platforming. Ultimately, it means like
allowing players to do I interacted with
a tweet from air yesterday about it
and and it sounds really obvious and
often like on Twitter everyone's like
everyone's trying to be like tactically
like
language relax
it's a little bit too much but there's
so much to learn it's great and I and I
read it all because I'm I want to learn
right
but Amir put it in like quite simple
terms and it was it was
some people go yeah I know that but I
was like this is a really good point and
the point was But you know, football is
about getting players to together and
going, "You don't like you don't like
dribbling with it, do you? You come here
and sit and you play pass the ball to
the guy who loves to dribble
and this guy does this guy wants to play
with his back to goal. Cool. You play
here, but we've got this really fast guy
as well. He wants to run in behind.
Okay, you two play together." So it
that's easier said than done.
And
I feel like Yeah, that's the thing for
me with this that I'm not sure we're
we're just not seeing that.
Yeah. I feel like it's a lot of square
pegs, round holes, you know what I
That's the thing with Amarim and as you
said a lot of stuff that we do see at
Sunday league level, grassroots level,
etc. they do translate to the to the
professional level. Exactly what you
just said. Some
the game's getting simpler.
Exactly. I promise you simp
Arsenal and again that's where I kind of
winced at some of the
some of the sort of Yeah. the tactical
language at times because it was like
essentially what Arsenal kind of done a
little bit and I I this is something I I
feel like is is coming back into the
game is is sort of a second striker
shadow striker or two up top really and
you saw it with like Yarez is running in
the channels like being a bit bullish
laying it off but you've already got
another guy up there already in in EZ to
give you that chance to go and do that.
So finding those different ways to do it
is
what's on paper now or what's on the
lineup when you see it. It's just not
it's kind of nonsense at this point.
No, it's all about roles, right? It's
all about roles. A lot of times people
think about positions and stuff, but
it's your role in that positions. For
example, like Cal Fury. Yeah. Okay. He
was a center back at once once upon a
time. But at left back, he is an
attacking left back. He's not an
inverted left backer. He's an attacking
left back doing what an attacking left
back should do. Overlapping. You're
looking at Timber solid in the other
side for example and I think Arteta his
issue actually was similar in terms of
not as extreme as Amarims but there was
points where you're looking at like
are you kind of square peg round holes
as well there was a little a bit of that
you know Havits in the midfield declin
was almost playing at number 10 at some
points in the season there was a little
bit of question marks you had like Mazu
Skelly or Ben White some things were
just not looking like it was the players
in the right positions but now he's just
simplif ified it again. The right back
is the right back. The left back is the
left back. Don Rice is back in a pivot
with Zuba Mendy. Ez, which he should be,
is it's very simple. So,
honestly, I feel like management is
starting to become a bit too
complicated. Way too complicated. But
that that comes down to data analysts
that there's so much there's so much
stuff that goes into why the game has
gone more complicated. But as you're
saying, it can just be simplified, man.
I think it can. I think you're right.
This is one question I want to ask you.
So, stay silent. We're talking about the
squad because that's the other thing
like how good is the squad because I
think you're if you're looking at Amarim
and you're trying to find the ifs and
the buts about it all you could suggest
that the squad's you know like we said
from that team that Fergie left and the
squad there to the squad that you've got
now
you know it's it has to be certainly
worse or less proven, right? So stay
silent,
okay,
until you hear a squad worse than Man
United.
squad worse
because you're talking about you're
talking about confidence which I think
is a really like character always says
it's never as bad as you think it's
never as good as you think and
confidence can make you just turn you
into a completely different player like
you we're doing we're working on a video
now about Palace and United and that
system but how
if you're playing with confidence and
knowing what you're going to do and
often confidence and competence are very
closely linked if I know where I've got
to go or I've got I know I've got
security behind me
then you will go and jump correctly or
at the right
Um and so that confidence is really
important and this Man United team is is
not high on confidence, right? And I
think that Arsenal game initially it was
sort of there was a bit of a reset.
Yeah.
And so everyone's thinking I've seen it
now. Watch them fly
and a lot of us say it like I I was like
I think this okay I get it. I see it
maybe
go. But when it comes to those
individual moments you got to score your
penalties when you get them
and you got to like you got to score
goals. You got to take your
opportunities. So the squad is kind of
it's up in the air and you know better
than me because you obviously you're a
United fan. So Liverpool,
Arsenal,
Tottenham,
Man City,
Chelsea.
Where do I want to go? Newcastle,
Aston Villa.
Crystal Palace.
I think we have a better score.
Look, okay, let me say right, Villa are
going for a bad moment. Forest, I think
we have a better squad. The thing about
Man United,
Forest got good squad. On paper,
the squad isn't too bad on paper. But
the thing is, right, for me, when I look
at the Man United squad is that just
like how you said, like in terms of what
air was saying, I don't think this
United squad are very cohesive in any
way. I don't feel our profiles match
each other.
I don't think Yeah, I don't think
players are going where they want to go.
Yeah, it don't. the profiles don't match
each other in terms of like I don't
think the like I don't think Bruno and
Casemiro for example as a pairing match
at all. You both want to kind of go long
at every opportunity. You're both very
direct. You both don't want to keep the
ball and retain it and so yes Bruno is a
good player. Yes, Casemiro he's actually
revitalized himself a little bit. you're
a good player, but
you don't you don't mesh. You don't mesh
well together. And I think that's
when all the parts around it don't help
that.
Exactly. Like you look at Benjamin
Cesco, for example. I'm looking at his
game so far. I'm learning about him cuz
I'm I wasn't too familiar with him at So
and I'm like,
how do you match Kuna's game?
Kuna is a shoot first player. that Kuna
doesn't really you can see why he not
not why he was at Wolves disrespectfully
but you can see why he was the hero at
Wolves he's very direct just like a
Bruno Fernandez he likes to shoot he
doesn't have that passing element so I'm
like but then you've got Cesco who
clearly likes to run in behind are you
going to be getting them passes from
Kuna do you know what I mean like these
are the question mark he's even looking
at you he's trying to get you Bumo who's
now
like him He likes to cross the ball a
lot which is good for Cesco but then
again he doesn't go by line. He just
crosses from deep.
Yeah.
And then Maz and then you've got Mazawi
who doesn't overlap. So yeah we're
saying all these good names but there's
not a cohesive team whereas you look at
Liverpool for not maybe not any top team
their right back matches with what the
winger was. Look at Liverpool last
season. Trent and Salah clearly their
games work together. You know what I
mean? Mallister and Grain Burch's games
work together. Now you got Shabbosai
who's improving.
That's what they're struggling with a
little bit. Liverpool is
in terms of control in the in the
midfield you're talking about. Yeah.
Oh no, no, sorry. In the terms of like
So I was watching with the Premier
League, we got this like tactical camp.
You watch the whole game and tact. Oh,
it's amazing.
And what was Canate is the moment Kate
slips. Yeah. And uh Mateta or gives the
ball away and Mateta's in. seen that on.
You might have seen on the highlights,
guys. But before that,
there's a moment where Kenate plays the
ball to Trent uh sorry to Connor
Bradley.
And if it was Trent, Trent would have
sort of opened up his body and gone boom
and Sal would have already gone and it
would have been a problem.
Yes.
Because the Palace line is naturally a
little bit higher up because you're, you
know, it's earlier in the phase of play.
Bradley looked up and he saw Gay and
Mitchell
like surrounding Salah
and understandably he's seen that and
gone well I'm not Trent I can't play I'm
going I'm going to go back
and so Salah doesn't get the ball
and Kate doesn't really want the ball
and that leads to his kuffle and he
slips and it goes from there. So yeah,
it's uh that balance is is really really
important. And again, we in the summer
we always go, okay, this should work
because blah blah blah blah. I'll make
videos on it. I do it.
So it should some of these things should
work, but what happens in time is that
you go, okay, you're not comfortable.
And so that's where the tweaks and
changes need to happen. How often do we
see this for from England where we see
players now England obviously a lot
higher level in terms of the player
quality but you see players and you
think okay on paper that just has to
make sense Foden in midfield with Jude
and Rice has to make sense
but it doesn't make sense let's be
honest you need Adam Walton you need a
Kobe Mayu which he did in the in the um
in the Euros you need someone else do
you know what I mean like you need
someone that's gonna match them profiles
okay Declan Rice can then be this
bombing on forward player because you've
got someone that can get the ball better
in the first phase or calm the game down
then Jude can be that attacking player.
We see it all the time. We've seen it
with Lampard and Gerard of England like
it can happen even with the best
players. So imagine now when you bring
the quality lower it's going to look
like a disaster and that's the thing
that I think on paper
the team smell blood as well cuz Man
United is a big it's a big catch. It's
always a big catch
and as I saying like for example Mayu
you bring even if you bring in Mayu and
you have Casemir and you have Bruno
there's no legs in that midfield.
So again
you been you've been clamoring for May
to be played right
100% like I feel like he
how do you how do you make it work? How
do you make this work
for me?
I am saying I don't know the ceiling of
Man United regardless isn't high. You
know what I mean? Regardless if we sack
Amarim and getting a new manager, I'm
looking at I think we can get be a top
eight team, top eight, top seven maybe.
Cuz I watched this video was talking
about the the uh
the managers that could take over if if
he was to make the change. And there's
some really interesting
issues.
Yeah.
That make it hard. So first of all, and
this often I say I think I said to Leah
here a couple of weeks ago,
the expect Carl Anker said this a great
point. It's like whenever you talk about
Man United, the manager always has to
answer answer this question. It's like
when are we going to be good again?
Yep.
Right.
But you don't go name a team.
Yeah.
Like if you think Arteta, if you think
Klopp, even think Guardiola,
it takes time. It takes seasons.
Right.
So when it comes to managers coming in
those the list of names I'm hearing is
it's Javi,
it's Hersler, it's Glasnner,
it's Southgate,
it's
Yeah. So all of them
I don't think I I don't think even with
um a better squad to get them from here
to here it's going to take two three
seasons right. So there's a sort of um
not an identity thing but there's a
there's a problem with the idea of like
how do you get them to be good again?
So
of that list of names you've also got
other decisions to make like bring in
Javi. So you're not going you're not
playing this free at the back anymore.
So you change from that. If you go with
Glasnar, you're doubling down on this
free at the back, right? So does that
make
is that who you are moving forward in
terms of Man United. If you bring in
Southgate,
people don't like it,
right? If you bring in Hersley, you're
too inexperienced. If you bring in
early, you might be too cavalier. So
these problems are going to keep like
you have to kind of get off your knees
before you can get anywhere near that.
Unless there's someone that you're just
like, "Wow, give this guy the keys." And
I think the thing that is being
forgotten in all of this
is that this essentially the style of
play, the formation, the squad building,
it's got nothing to do with the coach.
Yeah. Yeah. It should be
it should be just a known thing
essentially of like this is generally
the blueprint of Man United and so that
you can plug and play different head
coaches so that like if these guys
aren't getting the reaction that you
need
you can fail a bit faster
and go cuz the problem this is why you
still got the time is that people are
going
okay you can have the keys
we are going to commit to you because of
previous problems
and and it will be okay we just need to
give you time if we just do the thing
where if we behave well and give the
time you'll be fine.
That's that's the Fergie aspect of
things. That's the fact that we had
Fergie and we had Matt going all the way
back Matt Busby who two figureheads who
built this
I think that's a real really difficult
thing and because of that there's such a
onus on that manager
whereas it really if you look at
Liverpool and the squad building that
they have or Man City
or Arsenal I guess is getting to that
point as well maybe slightly less so it
gets to a point you have to get a
manager to get so good that okay now you
can have your
100%
instead of the other way around
at Man United we give managers Like
honestly, you get questioned about your
loyalty to the club if you question the
manager. It's insane. Like I feel like
we're the only club that are like that
where we have a manager on a pedestal
above players nearly above honestly
above ownership like the we give
managers because we had
right intention though.
Yeah. Because we had Sir Alex Ferguson
though and everybody grew up on and as I
said Matt Busby as well. So you got two
figureheads of the club. So managers
have always been like idols for this
club, but when you look at it, it
shouldn't really be like that. And I do
think that is where Mayad have gone
wrong over the years, especially with
Eric Tenhog cuz
his signings were crazy if in my
opinion, right? So it went really bad
with him and I do think Inos are trying
to sort that out. I think this summer in
Bumo, I think um Kuna, Cesco, I don't
really think they were necessarily amim
signings. I think they'll just we're
going to sign them and you got to make
it work type thing because they are
thinking
about what you said the progression in
the future if this manager goes these
guys need to be players that are going
to be at Man United for years whereas
you look at as I said 10 Hog signings it
was a bit different but previous
ownership wasn't like that previous
ownership gave the keys to all the
managers and each manager picks and
plugs who they want and then they get
sacked and then you're like we got to
revitalize this and it goes on and on.
Jose Mourinho first summer he came in he
basically got rid of everyone that
that that LVG bought you know what I
mean? So it's a it's a it's a cycle but
I do think Inos are trying to sort that
out. If I'm going to give them any bit
of credit I do think they're trying to
sort that out.
I think from what I've read about Danny
Ras or the thing I find slightly odd
here is the
the sort of fail there's a fail fast
mentality that he supposedly has with a
lot of his businesses. Now there's
because of the principles of Man United
like you said there I don't think that
that's what almost like hurting them a
little bit but again if you have that
clear structure of like this is who we
are this is how we play
then it comes you can you can go if you
can either fix it fast or fail fast
either way we can move on and get it
moving in the right direction.
Um but at the moment they seem a bit
like stunted by that. I feel like
they're I feel like they're not wanting
to accept that they made a mistake.
And it's weird because you accepted well
maybe something happened behind closed
doors that we don't know about, but you
kind of accepted that, okay, maybe Dan
Ashworth wasn't the right appointment.
You got rid of him really quickly. Was
that the right decision? We'll never
know. Maybe it wasn't. Who knows? But
then I feel like they're not trying to
do this with Amarin because
that's their first managerial
appointment and it was like this is the
beginning of the English era
and then especially because the signs
were there from last season.
I feel like they're really trying to
stick through because then if you sack
him now we're all going to say well why
didn't you sack him after the Europa
final
and there's and then it's going to that
mistake is even bigger. But I think
what you need to do
for me, I think it has to be done. I I
just You saw Carrago speaking about it
just the other day, and
again, as I always say, I feel like
rival or opposition fans and analysts
look at it from an objective point of
view, whereas we look at it from an
emotional point of view. It's gone too
far. Come on. It's gone too far.
Yeah. Um yeah I wanted you want to see
it you need this is the thing again and
this will be the cycle for the next guy
if the next guy comes in
if he does come in
and struggles
and and what you know struggling is not
not having really clear shoots of hope
he will have used that like foundation
of credit as I was talking about with
grand potter last week
and then the next five games of next
season it's the same thing there's so
much that's the thing that's that's the
thing that's hard for him as There's so
much pressure on him. But
like make it about YouTube and YouTube
and you make you go I'm going to try
this video see if it works and it really
doesn't work and then you go no but I
really like this idea.
Yeah.
I'm going to try it again and it doesn't
work.
But you there's series all up and down
loads of channels. They don't last.
Yeah. Yeah.
And you're better off stopping like you
you got to give it a bit of a chance.
But I think the older I get more I'm
kind of like for me I'm always like am I
seeing the right things? Is he been a
little bit unfortunate here or there?
Like for example the Arsenal Newcastle
game again goals from set pieces. So if
you want to just base it on that then
fine. But there was a lot of other
things that oh if that breaks if that
breaks if that breaks I can see
something.
Yeah.
I'm struggling. you're struggling to see
honestly like um the thing is other than
the generic term of give him time no
one's really coming with hardcore reason
as to why it says to him oh give him
time oh you know art needed time give
him we can't be looking at anomalies and
thinking that's the norm you know what I
mean so you're you you do a great job
analyzing games looking at things
working with Premier all this time and
you can't see something where it's like
you know what I mean other than the
general hey just give him time, you
know, it's going to
just
about answers.
Time could genuinely mean a relegation
battle.
Yeah,
it was nearly our season, so why not
this season?
I just Yeah, I agree. I just think
football's about football's about
answers. Yeah. And and this league this
year,
it's so physical, so quick. You don't
need the ball for long
to hurt teams. And
you see in Sunderland's physicality.
Sunderland are physical, man. That's
where we're standing. It was a Ballard
flipping out.
He's got nice center back's head.
Listen, he's ready.