Why do wide receivers prefer lower
jersey numbers? Well, in the NFL,
certain players are only allowed to
choose from certain numbers. Wide
receivers were originally only allowed
to wear between 80 and 89, but in 2004,
the NFL expanded this to include 10 to
19. The change saw an exodus of players
to the lower numbers. And by 2019, 181
of the 229 receivers in ESPN's player
database wore 10 to 19. Many changed for
branding reasons or to honor their
favorite player, but there were others
who claimed the lower numbers made them
faster, slimmer, and more agile. Now,
this may sound like superstition, but
there's actually science to back it up.
Two UCLA experiments found that
volunteers consistently said players in
jersey numbers 10 to 19 looked thinner
than those wearing 80 to 89, even when
the bodies were the same size. It's
theorized that this is because people's
previously learned associations between
numbers influence their perception of
body sizes. Meaning a lower number could
make you actually seem thinner.